[
  {
    "id": "1879",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:1",
    "question": "After King Benjamin was able to establish peace in the land of Zarahemla, he had continual peace all the remainder of his days.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1880",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:2",
    "question": "King Benjamin had five sons.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1881",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:2",
    "question": "King Benjamin caused that his sons be taught in all the language of his fathers that thereby they might become men of understanding.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1882",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos1:2",
    "question": "King Benjamin wanted his sons to know concerning the_____ which had been spoken by the mouths of their fathers.",
    "answer": ["Prophecies"],
    "options": ["Prophecies", "10 Commandments", "Law Of Moses"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1883",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:2",
    "question": "By whose hand were the prophecies delivered to the mouths of the prophets in the Book of Mosiah?  The",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1884",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:3",
    "question": "King Benjamin taught his sons concerning the records which were engraved on the_____ of brass.",
    "answer": ["Plates"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1885",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:3",
    "question": "Mosiah wrote that if it were not for the records and commandments written on them, they would have suffered in ignorance.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1886",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:3",
    "question": "Mosiah wrote that if it were not for the Plates of_____, they would have suffered in ignorance, not knowing the mysteries of God.",
    "answer": ["Brass"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1887",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:4",
    "question": "Mosiah said that it was not possible for Lehi to remember “all these things” and having taught them to his children if it was not for the help of the plates of brass.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1888",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:4",
    "question": "According to Mosiah, Lehi was taught in the language of the Egyptians and could read the things engraved on the plates.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1889",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:4",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote that Lehi taught his children in the language of the Egyptians thereby teaching their children and so forth, fulfilling the word of God down to his present time.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1890",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:5",
    "question": "King Benjamin said to his sons that if it were not for the plates of brass; the Nephites would have dwindled in unbelief.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1891",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos1:5",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote that if it were not for the plates of brass, the Nephites would have dwindled in unbelief and not known of the commandments of God or his_____.",
    "answer": ["Mysteries"],
    "options": ["Plans", "Mysteries", "Miracles"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1892",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:5",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the_____ know nothing concerning the things of God, or even do not believe them when they are taught, because of the traditions of their fathers.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1893",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos1:5",
    "question": "Who preserved the records and the plates of brass by their hand according to King Benjamin?",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["Nephi", "Lehi", "God"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1894",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:5",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the traditions of the Lamanites and their fathers, was correct.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1895",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:6",
    "question": "King Benjamin testified of the truthfulness of the sayings, records, and the plates of Nephi.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1896",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:6",
    "question": "The plates of_____, contain the records and sayings of the fathers of King Benjamin from the time they left Jerusalem until his present time.",
    "answer": ["Nephi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1897",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:6",
    "question": "King Benjamin testified of the surety of the records and of the plates of Nephi because they had them before their very eyes.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1898",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:7",
    "question": "King Benjamin wanted his sons to search the records diligently so they could profit from them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1899",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:7",
    "question": "King Benjamin told his sons that if they searched the records diligently, and keep the commandments of the Lord, they would prosper in the land, according to the_____ the Lord had made with their fathers.",
    "answer": ["Promise"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1900",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:8",
    "question": "All the things that King Benjamin taught his sons are written in the Book of Mosiah.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1901",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:9",
    "question": "When King Benjamin was thirty years old and soon go to his grave; he conferred the kingdom to one of his sons.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1902",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos1:9",
    "question": "King Benjamin decided to confer the kingdom to one of his sons because he_____ old and saw that he must soon go to the way of the earth.",
    "answer": ["Waxed"],
    "options": ["Waxed", "Grew", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1903",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:10",
    "question": "Who did King Benjamin confer the kingdom to, and was also one of his sons?",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1904",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:10-Mos2:1",
    "question": "Who made the first proclamation mentioned in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1905",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:10",
    "question": "King Benjamin wanted Mosiah to send out a proclamation to the people of Zarahemla and the people or Mosiah.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1906",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:10",
    "question": "King Benjamin wanted to proclaim out of his own mouth to the people that_____ would be their next king and a ruler over them.",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1907",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin wanted to give a people a name that thereby they may be distinguished above all the people the Lord God had brought out of Jerusalem.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1908",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin gave the people the name of Christ because they had been diligent in keeping the commandments of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1909",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:12",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the name that he gave the people of Zarahemla and Mosiah would never be_____ out, except it be; through transgression.",
    "answer": ["Blotted"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1910",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:12",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the name that he gave the people would never be blotted out except through transgression.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1911",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos1:13",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the people of Zarahemla and Mosiah were a highly favored_____ of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["People"],
    "options": ["Tribe", "People", "Bunch"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1912",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:13",
    "question": "If the people that are highly favored of the Lord should fall into transgression; the Lord would deliver them up and become a weak people like their brethren the_____.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1913",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:13",
    "question": "If the Nephites fall into transgression; the Lord will not preserve them by his_____ and marvelous power.",
    "answer": ["Matchless"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1914",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos1:14",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that if the Lord had not extended his_____ in the preservation of the Nephites, they would have fallen into the hands of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["Arm"],
    "options": ["Arm", "Power", "Wisdom"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1915",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:14",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the Lord extended his arm in the preservation of the Nephites so that they would not become victims of the hatred of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1916",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:15",
    "question": "After King Benjamin made an end of his sayings to his son, he gave him charge concerning all the affairs of the_____.",
    "answer": ["Kingdom"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1917",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:16",
    "question": "The ball or director led the fathers of King Benjamin through the wilderness according to the heed and_____ which they gave unto him.",
    "answer": ["Diligence"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1918",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:16 & Alma37:38",
    "question": "The Liahona led the fathers of King Benjamin through the wilderness according to the heed and diligence they gave unto the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1923",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos1:17",
    "question": "If the fathers of King Benjamin were unfaithful, they would not prosper neither_____ in their journey in the wilderness.",
    "answer": ["Progress"],
    "options": ["Be Blessed", "Progress", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1924",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:17",
    "question": "When the fathers of King Benjamin incurred the displeasure of God upon them; they were smitten with fam1ne and sore_____ to stir them up in remembrance of their duty.",
    "answer": ["Afflictions"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1925",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:18",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Mosiah did not do what his father King Benjamin commanded him to do by sending out a proclamation to the people.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1926",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:18",
    "question": "At what place did the people of Zarahemla and Mosiah gather together to hear the words of King Benjamin.",
    "answer": ["Temple"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1927",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos1:2",
    "question": "The people that gathered around the temple were so great, that they did not number them; for they had multiplied exceedingly and waxed great in the land.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1928",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mosiah2:1",
    "question": "What person in the Book of Mormon is the first one to make a proclamation unto the people?",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1929",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mosiah2:1",
    "question": "Who made the first proclamation unto the Nephites; King Benjamin or his son Mosiah?",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1930",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:3",
    "question": "The people took the_____ of their flocks, that they might offer sacrifice and burnt offerings according to the Law of Moses.",
    "answer": ["Worst"],
    "options": ["Worst", "Firstlings"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1931",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:4",
    "question": "The people offered sacrifice and burnt offerings to the Lord for the purpose of given him thanks for bringing them out of Jerusalem and delivering them from the hands of their enemies.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1932",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:4",
    "question": "Who appointed just men and teachers for the Nephites and also a just man to be their king in the land of Zarahemla and the land of Mosiah?",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1933",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:4",
    "question": "Who taught the people of Zarahemla to keep the commandments of God, that they might be filled with love towards God and all men?",
    "answer": ["Benjamin"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1934",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people pitched their tents around the temple to hear the words of King_____.",
    "answer": ["Benjamin"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1935",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:5",
    "question": "The people pitched their tents around the temple, according to his family from the eldest to the youngest, every family being separate one from another.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1936",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:6",
    "question": "In relation to the temple; in what direction did the people pitch the door of their tents toward the temple?",
    "answer": ["Facing The Temple"],
    "options": [
      "Facing The Temple",
      "North Of The Temple",
      "South Of The Temple."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1937",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:6",
    "question": "The multitude of the people was so great that King Benjamin could not teach them all within the wall of the_____.",
    "answer": ["Temple"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1938",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:7",
    "question": "King Benjamin caused that a_____ be erected so that he could speak to the people and that they could hear his words.",
    "answer": ["Tower"],
    "options": ["Tower", "Building", "Temple"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1939",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when King Benjamin started to speak to the people, not all of them could here his words.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1940",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:9",
    "question": "King Benjamin caused that the words which he should speak unto the people be written upon plates.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1941",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:9",
    "question": "What were the first two words that King Benjamin said to the people when he spoke to them in the tower.",
    "answer": ["Breathren"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1942",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:9",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people that he had not commanded them to trifle with the words he should speak, but to hearken unto him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1943",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:10",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people that he had not commanded them to gather together and should fear them, and think that he was more than a_____ man.",
    "answer": ["Better"],
    "options": ["Better", "Mortal"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1944",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that he was just like the people and subjected to all manner of infirmaties in body and mind.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1945",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that he had been consecrated by his father, and was suffered by the_____ of the Lord to be a king and ruler of the people.",
    "answer": ["Hand"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1946",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people that he had been preserved by the Lord’s matchless power, to serve them with all the might, mind and_____ which the Lord had granted unto him.",
    "answer": ["Strength"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1947",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:12",
    "question": "King Benjamin had suffered all his days in the service of his people and not sought after gold, or silver, or any manner of_____ from them.",
    "answer": ["Riches"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1948",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:13",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people; neither have I suffered that ye should be conf1ned to dungeons.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1949",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:13",
    "question": "King Benjamin would not suffer that the people make slaves of one another, nor that they should murder, plunder, steal, or commit_____.",
    "answer": ["Adultery"],
    "options": ["Adultery", "Crimes", "Crimes Against Humanity"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1950",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:13",
    "question": "King Benjamin would not suffer the people to commit any manner of_____, and had taught them to keep the commandments of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["Wickedness"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1951",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:14",
    "question": "King Benjamin said: “Even I, myself, have labored with m1ne own_____ that I might serve you, and that ye should not be laden with taxes”.",
    "answer": ["Hands"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1952",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:14",
    "question": "King Benjamin wanted that his people; to do nothing that was grievous to be borne of them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1953",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:14",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people that they were witnesses to all the things which he was speaking to them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1954",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:15",
    "question": "When King Benjamin spoke to the people on the tower; he wanted to boast of the things and service he had done for them.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1955",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos1:15",
    "question": "King Benjamin wanted the people to know that he could answer to_____ with a clear conscience.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1956",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:16",
    "question": "King Benjamin did not desire to boast to the people, but said that he had only been in the_____ of God.",
    "answer": ["Service"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1957",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:17",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people things so that they could learn_____.",
    "answer": ["Wisdom"],
    "options": ["Of God", "Wisdom", "Or How To Make Speeches"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1958",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:17",
    "question": "Who was the first person in the Book of Mormon to say the following words: “When ye are in the service of your fellow beings ye are only in the service of your God”.",
    "answer": ["Benjamin"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1959",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:17",
    "question": "King Benjamin taught his people wisdom by wanting them to learn, that when they were in service to their fellow beings they were only in the service of their_____.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1960",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:18",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that if he was the king and labored for the people, should they not labor to serve one another?",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1961",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:19",
    "question": "King Benjamin did not want the people to thank their heavenly King because he had labored all his days in the service of God and the people.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1962",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:20",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people that they should render all their thanks and praise which their soul possessed to that God that had created them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1963",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:20",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that God had created them and had kept and preserved them that they should live in______ with one another.",
    "answer": ["Peace"],
    "options": ["Peace", "Harmony", "Contention"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1964",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:21",
    "question": "What has the Lord lend unto us that we may live and move according to our own will, and supports us from one moment to another?",
    "answer": ["Breath"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1965",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:21",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that even if we were to serve God with all our whole souls, we would still be unprofitable servants.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1966",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:22",
    "question": "King Benjamin tells the Nephites and us: 'That all the Lord requires of us is to keep his commandments and we will prosper in the Land''.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1967",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:22",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the Lord varies from time to time of the things which he has said",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1968",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:23-24",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that because the Lord has created us and granted us our lives we are required to keep his commandments.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1969",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:23-24",
    "question": "According to King Benjamin we will always be indebted to our heavenly father, forever and ever.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1970",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:24",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that if we do what the Lord commands us to do, he will immediately bless us",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1971",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:25",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote that even the dust is greater than all of us.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1972",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2;25",
    "question": "King Benjamin testified and knew that we were created from the_____.",
    "answer": ["Dust"],
    "options": ["Earth", "World", "Dust"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1973",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:25",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote that because we were created from the dust of the earth; we do not belong to our heavenly father.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1974",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:26",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that even him, whom they called their king; was no better than them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1975",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:27",
    "question": "King Benjamin had caused that the people gather together that he might be found_____, and that there blood should not come upon him at judgment day.",
    "answer": ["Blameless"],
    "options": ["Blameless", "Spotless", "Unworthy"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1976",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:28",
    "question": "King Benjamin caused the people to assemble together that he might rid his_____ of their blood.",
    "answer": ["Garments"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1977",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:28",
    "question": "King Benjamin wished that he would go down in peace and that his spirit may join the_____ above in singing praises of a just God.",
    "answer": ["Choirs"],
    "options": ["Heavens", "Choirs", "Assemblies"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1978",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:28",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that God was only just when he wanted to be.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1979",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:29",
    "question": "King Benjamin had the people gather together to tell them that he could no longer be their teacher, nor their_____.",
    "answer": ["King"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1980",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:30",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people that even at this time, his whole frame trembled exceedingly while attempting to speak to them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1981",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:30",
    "question": "The_____ supported King Benjamin because his frame was trembling while he spoke to the people.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1982",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:30",
    "question": "Who commanded King Benjamin to declare to the people that his son Mosiah2 be the king and ruler of the Nephites?",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1983",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:31",
    "question": "Who did King Benjamin say would deliver the commandments of the Lord to the people?",
    "answer": ["Mosiah2"],
    "options": ["Mosiah2", "God", "Adam"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1984",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:32",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that contentions would arise among the people if they list to obey the evil spirit spoken by his father Mosiah.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1985",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:33",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote that if we choose to listen to the evil spirit and obey him, and remain and die in our sins, we will be drinking damnation to our soul.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1986",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:34",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the_____ that there were not any among them, except little children that had been taught the things of God.",
    "answer": ["Nephites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1987",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:34",
    "question": "During King Benjamin time, all the Nephites had been taught concerning the records except the little children.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1988",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:34",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that they were eternally indebted to their heavenly father and to render all that they have and are unto him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1989",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:36",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites if they should transgress and go contrary to that which had been spoken to them, the_____ of the Lord would withdraw from them.",
    "answer": ["Spirit"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1990",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:37",
    "question": "King Benjamin taught that those who openly rebel against God; “become an enemy to all_____”.",
    "answer": ["Righteousness"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1991",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:37",
    "question": "King Benjamin taught that if we openly rebel against God, we become an enemy to all righteousness; therefore, the Lord has no place for us.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1992",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:37",
    "question": "According to King Benjamin the Lord sometimes dwells in unholy temples.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1993",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:38",
    "question": "If we do not repent, and remain and die an enemy to God, the demands of div1ne justice will awaken our immortal soul to our guilt, and we will shrink from the presence of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1994",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:38",
    "question": "If we shrink from the presence of the Lord because of our guilt our breast will be filled with guilt, and_____, and anguish.",
    "answer": ["Pain"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1995",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:38",
    "question": "Our guilt, and pain, and anguish, is like an unquenchable fire, whose_____ ascends up forever and ever.",
    "answer": ["Flame"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1996",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:39",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that mercy has no claim on the man; therefore his final doom is to endure a_____-ending torment.",
    "answer": ["Never"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1997",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:40",
    "question": "King Benjamin spoke plainly to all the old men, young men, and little children.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1998",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos2:40",
    "question": "King Benjamin prayed that all the people should awake to a remembrance of the awful situation of those that had fallen into_____.",
    "answer": ["Transgression"],
    "options": ["The Bottomless Pit", "Transgression", "Hell"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1999",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:41",
    "question": "King Benjamin wanted his people to consider all the blessed and happy state of those that keep the commandments of God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2000",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:41",
    "question": "If we keep the commandments of God, we are blessed both temporally and spiritually.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2001",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos2:41",
    "question": "King Benjamin said if we are faithful to God to the end, we are received into heaven, that thereby we may dwell with him in a state of_____ happiness.",
    "answer": ["ending"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2002",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos2:41",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people that the things of which he had spoken of were somewhat true.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2003",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos3:2",
    "question": "The things that King Benjamin told the Nephites were made known unto him by_____.",
    "answer": ["Angel From God"],
    "options": ["Moses", "Nephi", "Angel From God"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2004",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:2",
    "question": "The angel told King Benjamin to awake, and he awoke, and behold he stood before him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2005",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:3",
    "question": "The angel of the Lord came to declare: “glad tidings of great joy” unto King _____.",
    "answer": ["Benjamin"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2006",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:4",
    "question": "The angel told King Benjamin that the Lord had judged him in righteousness and sent him to declare that he could rejoice.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2007",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:5",
    "question": "For behold, the time comes, and is not far distant, that with power, the Lord_____, who reigns, from all eternity to all eternity and shall come down from heaven among the children of men.",
    "answer": ["Omnipotent-"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2008",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:5",
    "question": "The Lord will not cure all manner of diseases.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2009",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:6-8",
    "question": "Who did King Benjamin say would cast out devils, or the evil spirits which shall dwell in the hearts of the children of men?",
    "answer": "Jesus",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2011",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:7",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote that Jesus Christ would bleed from every pore, and so great will be his anguish for the wickedness and the abominations of his people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2012",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:8",
    "question": "King Benjamin saw the crucifixion of Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2013",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:8-9",
    "question": "The word crucifixion never appears in the text of the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2014",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:8 & 2Nep25:19",
    "question": "What person in the Book of Mormon: is the second person to refer to the Savior by the name of Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": ["Benjamin"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "523",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:8",
    "question": "What is the name of the Savior's mother?",
    "answer": ["Mary"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2015",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:8",
    "question": "What prophet in the Book of Mormon is the first to mention the name of Mary as being the name of the mother of Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": ["Benjamin"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2016",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:8",
    "question": "Another name for Jesus Christ is the Creator of all things from the beginning.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2017",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:9",
    "question": "And lo, “He comes unto his own, and they shall consider him a man, and say that he has a devil, and shall scourge him, and_____ him”.",
    "answer": ["Crucify"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2018",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:10",
    "question": "And he shall rise the_____ day from the dead; and behold he stands to judge the world.",
    "answer": ["Third"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2019",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:10",
    "question": "The Lord will rise from the dead on the third day; and these things are done that a righteous judgment might come upon the children of men.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2020",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos3:11",
    "question": "Jesus Christ blood atones for the sins of those who have fallen by the transgression of_____.",
    "answer": ["Adam"],
    "options": ["Satan", "Adam", "Noah"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2021",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:11",
    "question": "According to King Benjamin, there are those who died not knowing the will of God concerning them, or who have ignorantly sinned.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2022",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:12",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote: “But woe, woe unto him who knows that rebels against God!",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2023",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:12",
    "question": "Salvation comes to none except it be through the repentance and_____ on the Lord Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": ["Faith"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2024",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos3:13",
    "question": "In the Book of Mosiah; Who did the Lord send to declare things among the children of men?_____",
    "answer": ["Holy Prophets"],
    "options": ["Peter", "Paul", "Holy Prophets"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2025",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:13",
    "question": "The Lord sent holy prophets to declare his things to every kindred, nation, and_____.",
    "answer": ["Tongue"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2026",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:13",
    "question": "The Lord wanted the people to receive a remission of their sins, and rejoice with exceeding great joy, even as though he had already come among them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2027",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:14",
    "question": "Because the people were stiffnecked, the Lord appointed to them a law which was called_____.",
    "answer": ["Moses"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2028",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:15",
    "question": "And many signs, and wonders, and types, were shown to the Nephites; and also holy prophets spoke concerning the coming of Christ, and yet they hardened their_____.",
    "answer": ["Hearts"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2029",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:16",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that it was not possible for little children to sin and even if they did, the blood of Jesus Christ atones for their sins.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2030",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:17",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote that there shall be no other name given, or any other way or means whereby salvation can come to the children of men, only in and through the name of Christ, the Lord Omnipotent.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2031",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:18",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that a baby that dies in infancy perishes.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2032",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:18",
    "question": "Who did King Benjamin say “he judges, and his judgment is just”?",
    "answer": ["Jesus"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2033",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos3:18",
    "question": "Men drink damnation to there own_____, except they humble themselves and become as little children, and believe that salvation was, and is to come, in and through the atoning blood of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": ["Souls"],
    "options": ["Bodies", "Souls", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2034",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:19",
    "question": "For the_____ man is an enemy to God, and has been since the fall of Adam.",
    "answer": ["Natural"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2035",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:19",
    "question": "The natural man is an enemy to God, and will be forever and ever, unless he yields to the enticing of the Holy Spirit.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2036",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:19",
    "question": "We must put off the natural man and become as a child, submissive, meek, and humble and yield to the enticing of the Holy Spirit.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2037",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:19",
    "question": "We must be willing to submit to all things which the_____ sees fit to inflict upon us, even as a child does submit to his father.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2038",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:20",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the time shall come when the knowledge of the_____ shall spread throughout every nation, kindred, tongue and people.",
    "answer": ["Savior"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2039",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos3:21",
    "question": "And behold, when the time comes, none shall be found blameless before God, except it be_____ children, only through repentance and faith on the name of the Lord God Omnipotent.",
    "answer": ["Little"],
    "options": ["Little", "Ugly", "Cute"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2040",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:23",
    "question": "King Benjamin spoke the words that the Lord had commanded him to speak to the Nephites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2041",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:24",
    "question": "The words which King Benjamin spoke to the Nephites while he was on the tower will not stand as a bright testimony against them.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2042",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:24",
    "question": "Thus saith the Lord:  “wherefore they shall be judged, every man according to his works, whether they be good, or whether they be_____”.",
    "answer": ["Evil"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2043",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos3:25",
    "question": "If your works were evil; you are consigned to an awful view of your own guilt and abominations, and an endless torment, from where you cannot return to the Lord’s presence.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2044",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos3:26",
    "question": "If you drink damnation to your soul, you have drunk out of the cup of the_____ of God.",
    "answer": ["Wrath"],
    "options": ["Tea", "Coffee", "Wrath"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2045",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:26",
    "question": "Adam fell because he partook of the_____ fruit.",
    "answer": ["Forbidden"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2046",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:27",
    "question": "If we go to hell our torment it is a lake of fire and_____, whose flames are unquenchable, and whose smoke ascends up forever and ever.",
    "answer": ["Brimstone"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2047",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:1",
    "question": "When King Benjamin was ending his address to the Nephites, he cast his eyes round about the multitude, and behold, they had fallen to the earth.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2048",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:2",
    "question": "The people that were at King Benjamin’s address fell to the earth, because the fear of the Lord had come upon them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2049",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:3",
    "question": "When King Benjamin finished his address to the Nephites; they viewed themselves in their own_____ state, even less than the dust of the earth.",
    "answer": ["Carnal"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2050",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos4:3",
    "question": "At the end of King Benjamin’s address; how did the people know that they had received forgiveness for their sins?",
    "answer": ["Were Filled With Joy"],
    "options": [
      "Burning Chest Sensation",
      "Were Filled With Joy",
      "Had A Halo Placed Of Their Heads"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2051",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:3",
    "question": "The people had exceeding_____ in Jesus Christ who should come, according to the words which King Benjamin had spoken unto them.",
    "answer": ["Faith"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2052",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:5",
    "question": "When King Benjamin spoke of man’s “nothingness” he was referring that we all depend on God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2053",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:6",
    "question": "King Benjamin spoke to the people of the knowledge and goodness of God, and his matchless power.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2054",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:7",
    "question": "King Benjamin said the atonement was prepared from the_____ of the world.",
    "answer": ["Foundation"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2055",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:9",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites and wrote to us to believe in God; believe that he is, and that he created all things, both in heaven and in earth.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2056",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:10",
    "question": "King Benjamin said we must repent of our sins and forsake them, and humble ourselves before God; and ask in sincerity of heart that he would forgive us, then we should_____ that we do them.",
    "answer": ["See"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2057",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:11",
    "question": "According to King Benjamin we should repent of our sins and should always retain in remembrance, the greatness of God, and our own nothingness, and his long-suffering towards us.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2058",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin told his people that they should not be calling on the name of the Lord daily.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2059",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin told his people that they should be standing steadfastly in the faith of that which is to come, which was spoken by the mouth of the angel.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2060",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin said as we come to the knowledge of the_____ of God, we will have known of his goodness and have tasted of his love.",
    "answer": ["Glory"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2061",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos4:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin said when we come to the knowledge and_____ of God; we will have received a remission of our sins, and it will cause exceeding great joy in our soul.",
    "answer": ["Glory"],
    "options": ["Glory", "Love", "Gift"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2062",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:12",
    "question": "If we are filled with the love of God, and always retain a remission of our sins; we shall grow in the knowledge of the glory of him that created us, or in the knowledge of that which is just and true.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2063",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:14",
    "question": "King Benjamin taught that our children must not_____ and quarrel one with another and serve the devil.",
    "answer": ["Fight"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2064",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:14",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the_____ is the master of sin, or who is the evil spirit spoken by his fathers, and is an enemy to all righteousness.",
    "answer": ["Devil"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2065",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:15",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that we should teach our children to walk in the ways of truth and soberness; to teach them to love one another, and to serve one another.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2066",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:16,18",
    "question": "King Benjamin said we have great cause to repent if we do not succor those that stand in need of our succor.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2067",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos4:19",
    "question": "King Benjamin said “for behold, are we not all_____? Do we not all depend upon the same Being, even God, for all our substance?”",
    "answer": ["Beggars"],
    "options": ["People", "Human", "Beggars"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2068",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:20",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that the Lord caused the hearts of the Nephites to be filled with joy because the Lord had poured out his Spirit upon them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2069",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:21",
    "question": "King Benjamin wrote that God will grant unto us whatsoever we ask that is right, in faith, believing that we will receive.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2070",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:21",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that not only had God created them, but that they were dependent on him for their lives, and for all that they have and are.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2071",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:22",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that our lives and all our substance belongs to_____, who has created us.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2072",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:24",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that we should not deny the beggar, because we have not; I would that ye say in your hearts that: “I give not because I have not, but if I had I would give”.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2073",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos4:26",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that we should impart of our substance unto the_____, every man according to what he has.",
    "answer": ["Poor"],
    "options": ["Poor", "Needy", "Homeless"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2074",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos4:27",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that we should see that all things are done in_____ and in order.",
    "answer": ["Wisdom"],
    "options": ["Correctly", "Wisdom", "Right Way"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2075",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:27",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that it is not “requisite that a man should run faster than he has strength”.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2076",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos4:28",
    "question": "We commit a sin when we borrow a tool from our neighbor and then don’t return it; and perhaps we shall cause that our neighbor might commit a sin also.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2077",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:29",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the_____ that there are so many ways to commit sin that he could not number them.",
    "answer": ["Nephites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2078",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos4:29",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites and us, to watch ourselves in our thoughts, and in our words, and in our_____, and observe the commandments of God.",
    "answer": ["Deeds"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2079",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos5:2",
    "question": "When King Benjamin spoke to the people it brought a mighty change in them and also in their hearts because of the Spirit of the Lord_____.",
    "answer": ["Omnipotent"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2080",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos5:2",
    "question": "Because to Spirit of the Lord Omnipotent had brought a mighty change in their hearts, the Nephites had no more disposition; to do_____, but to do good continually.",
    "answer": ["Evil"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2081",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos5:4",
    "question": "It was their faith that brought the great change in the people of King Benjamin",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2082",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos5:4",
    "question": "It was by_____ in the things that King Benjamin had spoken to them; that the people had no more disposition to do evil, but do good continually.",
    "answer": ["Faith"],
    "options": ["Witnessing", "Wisdom", "Faith"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2083",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos5:5",
    "question": "The people at King Benjamin address entered a covenant with God to do his will, and to be obedient to his commandments.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2085",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos5:6",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that they had not made a righteous covenant with the Lord.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2086",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos5:7",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the people because of the covenant they had made with the Lord was a righteous covenant; that they would be called the children of_____.",
    "answer": ["Christ"],
    "options": ["Moses", "Christ", "Paul"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2087",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos5:8",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that “there is no other name given whereby salvation comes” therefore, I would that ye should take upon you the name of Christ.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2088",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos5:9",
    "question": "According to King Benjamin; at the end of our lives it is better for us to be found on the right hand of God than of the left.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2089",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos5:9",
    "question": "King Benjamin said that if we take upon the name of Christ and be obedient unto the end of our lives, we shall be found on the_____ hand of God.",
    "answer": ["Right"],
    "options": ["Left", "Right", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2090",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos5:9",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that they would know the name by which they are called.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2091",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos5:10",
    "question": "King Benjamin said to the Nephites that if they did not take upon them the name of Christ, they must be called by some other name; therefore, they would find themselves on the_____ hand of God.",
    "answer": ["Left"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2092",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos5:11",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that there names would never be blotted out, except it be through transgression.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2093",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos5:12",
    "question": "King Benjamin told his people should not be found on the left hand of God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2094",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos5:12",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites that they should here and know; the_____ by which ye shall be called, and also, the name by which he shall call you.",
    "answer": ["Voice"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2095",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos5:13",
    "question": "For how knows a man the_____ whom he has not served, and also is a stranger unto him.",
    "answer": ["Master"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2096",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos5:15",
    "question": "King Benjamin told the Nephites and us that we should be steadfast and_____, always abounding in good works.",
    "answer": ["Immovable"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2097",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos6:1",
    "question": "When King Benjamin finished speaking to the people, he thought that it was expedient that he should take the names of the people who had entered a covenant with God to keep his commandment.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2098",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos6:2",
    "question": "And it came to pass that every soul and all the little children that had entered into a covenant had taken upon them the name of Christ.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2099",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos6:3",
    "question": "What kind of people did King Benjamin appoint at the end of his reign to remind the people of the oath they had made with the Lord?",
    "answer": ["Priests"],
    "options": ["Prophets", "Teachers", "Priests"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2100",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos6:4",
    "question": "How old was Mosiah2 when he began to reign in his father’s stead?",
    "answer": ["30"],
    "options": ["25", "30", "35"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2101",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos6:5",
    "question": "After King Mosiah2 began his reign; how many more years did King Benjamin live?",
    "answer": ["3"],
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2102",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos6:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Mosiah2 did not walk in the ways of the Lord, and was an unrighteous king.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2103",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos6:6",
    "question": "King Mosiah2 did walk in the ways of the Lord, and did observe his judgments and statues.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2104",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos6:7",
    "question": "King Mosiah2 caused that his people till the earth.  And he himself tilled the_____; that thereby he might not become a burden to his people.",
    "answer": ["Earth"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2105",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos6:7 & Mos7:1",
    "question": "King Mosiah2 had no contentions and had continual peace for the first three years of his reign.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2106",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:1",
    "question": "King Mosiah2 desired to know what had become of the people who went up to dwell in the land/city called Lehi-Nephi.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2107",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos7:2",
    "question": "King Mosiah2 granted that_____ of his strong men go up to the land of Lehi-Nephi to inquire concerning their brethren.",
    "answer": ["16"],
    "options": ["15", "16", "17"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2108",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:3",
    "question": "One of the men sent by King Mosiah2 to look for their brethren; was_____, and he is a descendant of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": ["Ammon"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2109",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:3",
    "question": "Ammon was a strong and mighty man, and a descendant of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2110",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:3",
    "question": "Ammon was not the leader on the band of sixteen men who went to the land of Lehi-Nephi to inquire about their brethren.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2113",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:7",
    "question": "Ammon and his brothers were surrounded by the king’s guard and were taken, and were bound, and were committed to prison.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2114",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:8",
    "question": "Ammon and his brothers were in prison for three days before they were brought before the king and permitted to speak.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2115",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:8",
    "question": "What was the name of the king who commanded that Ammon and his brothers to answer his questions?",
    "answer": ["_____Limhi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2116",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:9",
    "question": "What was the name of King Limhi’s father who was a wicked man and king of the land known as Lehi-Nephi?",
    "answer": ["Noah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2117",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:9",
    "question": "King Noah was the son of_____, who came up out of the land of Zarahemla to inherit the land of his fathers.",
    "answer": ["Zeniff"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2118",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos7:9",
    "question": "King Limhi was chosen to be the king of the land by:",
    "answer": ["Voice Of The People"],
    "options": [
      "Played Paper, Rock, Scissors,",
      "Popular Vote",
      "Voice Of The People"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2119",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:12",
    "question": "When Ammon was permitted to speak to King Limhi, he bowed himself before the king and endeavored to speak with boldness.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2120",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:13",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that if he would have known who he was, he would not have caused that he and his brethren be bound and put in prison.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2121",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:13",
    "question": "Ammon did not tell King Limhi that he was a descendant of Zarahemla, and did not come up to his land to inquire concerning the brethren, whom Zeniff brought up out of that land.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2122",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:14",
    "question": "King Limhi was exceedingly glad when_____ told him who he was and why they were inquiring of their brethren.",
    "answer": ["Ammon"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2123",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:15",
    "question": "King Limhi told Ammon that he and his people were in bondage to the_____, and were taxed with a tax which was grievous to be borne.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2124",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:15",
    "question": "King Limhi said to Ammon that is better to be slaves to the_____ than to pay tribute to the king of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["Nephites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2125",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:16",
    "question": "King Limhi commanded his guards that they should no more bind Ammon and his brethren that thereby they might eat, and_____, and rest themselves from their labors of their journey.",
    "answer": ["Drink"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2126",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos7:16",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren had suffered many things; they had suffered hunger, thirst, and_____; from the labors of their journey.",
    "answer": ["Fatigue"],
    "options": ["Fatigue", "Poisonous Snakes", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2127",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos7:17",
    "question": "King Limhi sent a_____ among all his people so that they could gather together at the temple to hear his words.",
    "answer": ["Proclamation"],
    "options": ["Epistle", "Letter", "Proclamation"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2128",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:19",
    "question": "King Limhi told his people; lift up your heads, and rejoice, and put your trust in me and Ammon.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2129",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:19",
    "question": "King Limhi told his people to put their trust in God, in that God who was the God of Abraham, and Isaac, and_____.",
    "answer": ["Jacob"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2130",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:19",
    "question": "King Limhi knew that God had brought the children of Israel out of the land of_____.",
    "answer": ["Egypt"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2131",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:19",
    "question": "King Limhi said that God had caused that the children of Israel should walk through the _____ Sea on dry ground.",
    "answer": ["Red"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2132",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:19",
    "question": "King Limhi wrote that God fed the Israelites_____ that they might not perish in the wilderness, and many more things did he do for them.",
    "answer": ["Manna"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2133",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:20",
    "question": "King Limhi said it is because of our iniquities and abominations that they were brought into bondage to the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2134",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:21",
    "question": "Who did King Limhi say was over-zealous to inherit the land of his fathers and was deceived by the cunning and craft1ness of King Laman?",
    "answer": ["Zeniff"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2135",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:21 & Mos9:5-8",
    "question": "In the Book of Mosiah; what over-zealous king entered into a treaty with the king of the Lamanites?",
    "answer": ["Zeniff"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2136",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:22",
    "question": "King Limhi told Ammon that they pay one half of the amount of every thing that they possess to the king of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2137",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos7:24",
    "question": "King Limhi told the people that they had reason to mourn because many of their brethren had been slain, and their blood had been spilled in vain, and all because of_____.",
    "answer": ["Iniquity"],
    "options": ["Bad Judgments", "Iniquity", "Abominations"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2138",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:25",
    "question": "If the people of King Limhi had not fallen into transgression the_____ would not have suffered that they have or go though the afflictions which they had.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2139",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:25",
    "question": "King Limhi said that the people would not hearken unto his words; but there arose contentions among them, even so much that they did shed_____ among themselves.",
    "answer": ["Blood"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2140",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:26",
    "question": "King Limhi said that a prophet of the Lord have they slain; a chosen man of God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2141",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:26-28",
    "question": "What prophet of the Lord if first mentioned in the Book of Mosiah chapter #7 versus 26 through 28 but were are not given his name?",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2142",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:26 & Mos17:20",
    "question": "What prophet of the Lord is considered by many Book of Mormon scholars to be the first person martyred in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2143",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:26",
    "question": "What prophet of the Lord did King Limhi say was slain because he told them of their wickedness and abominations?",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2144",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:26",
    "question": "Abinidi also prophesied of many things which are to come, yea, even of the coming of Christ.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2145",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:27",
    "question": "Abinidi testified that Christ was the God, the Father of all things, and said that he should take upon him the image of_____.",
    "answer": ["Man"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2146",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:27",
    "question": "Abinidi testified that man was created after the image of God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2147",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:28",
    "question": "Abinidi said that God should come down among the children of men, and take upon him flesh and_____, and go forth upon the face of the earth.",
    "answer": ["Blood"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2148",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:28",
    "question": "Because Abinidi said many things, the priests of Noah put him to death and brought the wrath of God upon them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2149",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos7:31",
    "question": "The Lord has said: “If my people shall sow filth1ness they shall reap the_____ wind, which brings immediate destruction”.",
    "answer": ["East"],
    "options": ["East", "West", "South"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2150",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:32",
    "question": "King Limhi said: “And now, behold, the promise of the Lord is fulfilled, and ye are smitten and afflicted”.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2151",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos7:33",
    "question": "King Limhi told his people to turn to the Lord with a full purpose of_____, and put their trust in him, and serve him with all diligence of mind.",
    "answer": ["Heart"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2152",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos7:33",
    "question": "If we turn to the Lord with a full purpose of heart, and put our trust in him, and serve him with all diligence of mind; he will, according to his own will and pleasure, deliver us out of any bondage we are in.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2153",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:1",
    "question": "All the things that King Limhi spoke to the Nephites are written in the Book of Mosiah.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2154",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:2",
    "question": "King Limhi caused that Ammon should stand up before the multitude, and rehearse unto them all that had happened unto their brethren from the time Zeniff went out of the land to the present time.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2155",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:3",
    "question": "Ammon rehearsed unto the people of King Limhi the last words that King_____ had taught them, so that they might understand all the words which he spoke.",
    "answer": ["Benjamin"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2156",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Limhi caused that the plates which conta1ned the record of his people be brought before_____; that he might read them.",
    "answer": ["Ammon"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2157",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:6",
    "question": "As soon as Ammon had read the record, King Limhi inquired of him to know if he could interpret languages.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2158",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:6",
    "question": "Ammon was well versed in the art of interpreting languages so it was very easy for him to interpret the thing that King Limhi desired of him.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2159",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:7",
    "question": "King Limhi caused that forty-three of his people should take a journey into the wilderness, to look for the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2160",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:7",
    "question": "The reason King Limhi sent forty-three of his people to look for_____ was that they might appeal to their brethren to deliver them out of bondage.",
    "answer": ["Zarahemla"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2161",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:8",
    "question": "The forty-three people that King Limhi sent to find Zarahemla; were diligent but they were not able to find the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2162",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:8",
    "question": "King Limhi’s people traveled on a land among many waters, having discovered a land which was covered with the bones of_____, and of beasts.",
    "answer": ["Men"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2163",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:8",
    "question": "The land that King Limhi’s people traveled was covered with ruins of buildings of every kind.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2164",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:8",
    "question": "King Limhi’s people discovered a land which had been peopled with a people who were as numerous as the hosts’ of_____.",
    "answer": ["Israel"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2165",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos8:9",
    "question": "King Limhi’s people brought back_____ plates filled with engravings as a testimony of the things they have said were true.",
    "answer": ["24 Or (25)"],
    "options": ["23", "24 Or (25)"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2166",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos8:9",
    "question": "The twenty-four plates that the people of Kim Limhi brought back with them and were filled with engravings and were made out of pure_____.",
    "answer": ["Gold"],
    "options": ["Brass", "Silver", "Gold"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2167",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:10",
    "question": "The people of King Limhi also brought back with them breastplates which were large.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2168",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:10",
    "question": "The breastplates that the people of King Limhi brought back with them were large and made of brass and copper, and were perfectly sound.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2169",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:11",
    "question": "And again, they have brought_____, the hilts thereof have perished, and the blades thereof were cankered with rust.",
    "answer": ["Swords"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2171",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:12",
    "question": "King Limhi desired that the records be translated because they might give him knowledge of a remnant of the people who have been destroyed and from whence the records came.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2172",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:13",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that he could translate the twenty-four plates because he had been given the gift of translating by God.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2173",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos8:13",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that he could not translate the records but that he knew of a man that could translate all records that are of ancient date; and it is a_____ of God.",
    "answer": ["Gift"],
    "options": ["Record", "Thing", "Gift"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2174",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:13",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that the man possessed things which were called interpreters that enable him to translate.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2175",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:13",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that no man can look in the interpreters except he be commanded by God, lest he should look for that he ought not and he should perish.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2176",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:13",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that whosoever is commanded to look in them, the same is called a_____.",
    "answer": ["Seer"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2177",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:13 & Mos21:28",
    "question": "The man that was able to look at the interpreters and not perish lived in the land of Zarahemla and was also their king; what was his name?",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2178",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:14",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that King Mosiah2 had been given this high gift from God to be able to translate records of ancient date",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2179",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:15",
    "question": "King Limhi asked Ammon if a seer is greater than a prophet.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2180",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:16",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that a seer is a_____ and a prophet also.",
    "answer": ["Revelator"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2181",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:16",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that no man can have a greater gift given to him, except he should possess the power of God, which no man can.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2182",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos8:16",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that a man can have great_____ given to him from God.",
    "answer": ["Power"],
    "options": ["Power", "Knowledge", "Wisdom"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2183",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:17",
    "question": "Ammon said that a seer can know of things which are past, and also of things which are to____, and by them shall all things be revealed.",
    "answer": ["Come"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2184",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:17",
    "question": "Ammon told King Limhi that though and by a seer shall secret things be made manifest.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2185",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:17",
    "question": "Ammon said through a seer hidden things shall come to light, and things which are not known shall be made known by him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2186",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos8:18",
    "question": "Ammon said that God has provided a means that man, through_____, might work mighty miracles.",
    "answer": ["Faith"],
    "options": ["The Atonement", "Faith", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2187",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:18",
    "question": "God has provided a means that man, through faith might work mighty miracles, therefore becoming a great benefit to his fellow beings.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2188",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:19",
    "question": "When Ammon was done speaking to King Limhi about what a seer and the interpreters can do for man, the king did not rejoice exceedingly.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2189",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:19",
    "question": "King Limhi told Ammon that it is doubtless a great mystery is conta1ned within these plates; and those interpreters were doubtless prepared for the purpose of unfolding all such_____ to the children of men.",
    "answer": ["Mysteries"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2190",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos8:20",
    "question": "“O how_____ are the works of the Lord, and how long does he suffer with his people”.",
    "answer": ["Marvelous"],
    "options": ["Marvelous", "Great", "Unimaginable"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2191",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos8:20",
    "question": "How blind and impenetrable are the understandings of the children of men; for they will not seek wisdom, neither do they desire that_____ shall rule over them.",
    "answer": ["She"],
    "options": ["She", "He", "It"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2192",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos8:21",
    "question": "King Limhi said that the children of men are as a wild flock which flee from the shepherd, and scattered, and are driven, and are devoured by the beasts of the forest.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2193",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9-22 & Mos7:21",
    "question": "In the Book of Mosiah, chapters 9 though 22 inclusively give the record of King Zeniff.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2194",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9 Heading",
    "question": "The record of King Zeniff gives an account of his people, from the time they left the land of_____ until the time that they were delivered out of the hands of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["Zarahemla"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2195",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:1",
    "question": "Zeniff was not taught in all of the language of the Nephites, but only in some parts.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2196",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:1",
    "question": "Zeniff was taught in all the language of the_____ and had a knowledge of the land of Nephi or of the land of his fathers first inheritance.",
    "answer": ["Nephites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2197",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:1",
    "question": "Zeniff was sent as_____ among the Lamanites that he might spy out their forces, that their army might come upon them and destroy them.",
    "answer": ["Spy"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2198",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:1",
    "question": "When Zeniff saw that which was good among them (Lamanites) I was desirous that they should not be destroyed.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2199",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:2",
    "question": "Zeniff contended with his brethren that their ruler would make a treaty with the_____.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2200",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:2",
    "question": "Zeniff said that the ruler of their army was an austere and a blood_____ man and commanded that Zeniff be slain.",
    "answer": ["Thirsty"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2201",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:2",
    "question": "Zeniff said that he was rescued by the shedding of much blood; for father fought against father, and brother against brother, until the greater of their army was destroyed in the wilderness.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2202",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:3",
    "question": "Zeniff and his brethren were smitten with fam1ne and sore afflictions because they “were slow to remember the Lord their _____”.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2203",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:5",
    "question": "Zeniff took four of his men into the city, in unto the king that he may know of the disposition of the king.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2204",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:6",
    "question": "The king of the Lamanites coveted with Zeniff that he might possess the land of Lehi-Nephi, and the land of Shilom.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2205",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:10",
    "question": "The name of the king that coveted with Zeniff that he could possess the land of Lehi-Nephi is King_____.",
    "answer": ["LamanI"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2206",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:7",
    "question": "King Laman1 did not command the people to leave the land of Lehi-Nephi so that Zeniff and his people could possess it.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2207",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:8",
    "question": "Zeniff and his people began to build buildings, and to repair the walls of the city of Lehi-Nephi and of the city of Shilom.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2208",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos9:9",
    "question": "Zeniff and his people began to till the ground, yea, even will all manner of_____, with seeds of corn, wheat, barley, and with seeds of all manner of fruit.",
    "answer": ["Seeds"],
    "options": ["Seeds", "Tools", "Mach1nery"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2209",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:9",
    "question": "Zeniff and his people did not begin to multiply and to prosper in the land because of their slow remembrance of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2210",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:10",
    "question": "It was the cunning and the craft1ness of King_____; that brought Zeniff and his people into bondage, that he yielded up the land that they might possess it.",
    "answer": ["LamanI"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2211",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos9:11",
    "question": "Zeniff and his people dwelt in the land for_____ years; before King Laman1 began to grow uneasy.",
    "answer": ["12"],
    "options": ["3", "6", "12"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2212",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:11",
    "question": "King Laman began to grow uneasy about Zeniff and his people because he feared that they would wax strong in the land, and he could not overpower them and bring them into bondage.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2213",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos9:12",
    "question": "Zeniff wrote that the Lamanites were a lazy and_____ people, and were desirous to bring them into bondage.",
    "answer": ["Idolatrous"],
    "options": ["Dark", "Idolatrous", "Idle"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2214",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:12",
    "question": "Zeniff wrote the Lamanites did not want to glut themselves with the labors of the hands of his people.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2215",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:12",
    "question": "Zeniff said the Lamanites wanted to feast themselves upon the flocks of their fields.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2216",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:13",
    "question": "Therefore it came to pass that King Laman1 began to stir up his people that they would contend with_____ and his people.",
    "answer": ["Zeniff"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2217",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:13,14",
    "question": "In the thirteenth year of the reign of King Zeniff there began to be wars and contentions in the land.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2218",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos9:14",
    "question": "The Lamanites began to slay the people of Zeniff and to take off with their flocks, and the_____ of the fields.",
    "answer": ["Corn"],
    "options": ["Corn", "Rice", "Potatoes"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2219",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:16",
    "question": "King Zeniff began to arm his people with bows and arrows, with swords, and with cimeters.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2220",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:16",
    "question": "King Zeniff’s people had clubs, slings, and all manner of weapons of_____ they could invent to fight against the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["War"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2221",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:17",
    "question": "Zeniff and his people had the strength of the_____ when they went to battle against the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2222",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:17",
    "question": "Zeniff and his people used their own bodily strength to fight the armies of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2223",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:17",
    "question": "King Zeniff and his people did cry mightily unto the Lord that he would deliver them out of the hands of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2224",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos9:17",
    "question": "Because King Zeniff and his people had cried mightily unto the Lord, they were awakened of the deliverance of their_____.",
    "answer": ["Fathers"],
    "options": ["Daughters", "Brothers", "Fathers"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2225",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:18",
    "question": "The Lord did not hear the cries of Zeniff and his people therefore he did not deliver them out of the hands of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2226",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos9:18",
    "question": "King Zeniff’s people went with the might of the Lord against the_____, and did drive them out of their lands.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2227",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos9:18",
    "question": "In one day and a night the people of King Zeniff did slay three thousand and forty-three Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2228",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos9:19",
    "question": "King Zeniff, himself, with his own _____ did bury the dead.",
    "answer": ["Hands"],
    "options": ["Shovel", "Hands", "Arms"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2229",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:1",
    "question": "King Zeniff and his people began to establish the kingdom and did establish peace throughout the land and also to possession of it again.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2230",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Zeniff had his people made all kinds of weapons of war in case the Lamanites might come up to war with his people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2231",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:2",
    "question": "King Zeniff caused that guards be place round about throughout the land so they would be aware if the Lamanites should come upon them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2232",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:5",
    "question": "King Zeniff caused that the Nephite woman should spin, and toil, and to work all manner of f1ne_____.",
    "answer": ["L1nen"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2233",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos10:5",
    "question": "King Zeniff caused that the women of his people work all manner of cloth so they might clothe their_____.",
    "answer": ["Nakedness"],
    "options": ["Bodies", "Nakedness", "Tents"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2234",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:6-Mos24:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Laman1 died, and his_____ began to reign in his stead.",
    "answer": ["Son"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2235",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:6-Mos24:3",
    "question": "What is the name of the king who succeeded King Lamam I?",
    "answer": ["Laman"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2236",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:6",
    "question": "King Laman2 began to stir his people up in rebellion against the people of King Zeniff.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2237",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos10:7",
    "question": "King Zeniff sent_____ out round about the land of Shemlon, that he might discover the plans and preparations of King Laman2 and his people.",
    "answer": ["Spies"],
    "options": ["Spies", "People", "Teancum"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2238",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:8",
    "question": "King Laman2’s men were armed with bows and arrows, and with swords, and with cimeters, and with stones, and with _____.",
    "answer": ["Slings"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2239",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos10:8",
    "question": "King Zeniff wrote that the Lamanites that came up against them to war had their_____ shaven.",
    "answer": ["Legs"],
    "options": ["Legs", "Chests"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2240",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:8",
    "question": "King Zeniff said that the Lamanites were naked; and they were girded with a leather girdle about their loins.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2241",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass the King Zeniff caused that the women and children of his people should hide in the_____.",
    "answer": ["Wilderness"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2242",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:9",
    "question": "King Zeniff also had his old men and also all the young men that were able to bear arms, that they should gather themselves together to do battle with the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2243",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:9",
    "question": "King Zeniff did not have all the old men and the young men that could bear arms gather together in their ranks, every man according to his age.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2244",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:10",
    "question": "In the Book of Mosiah; King Zeniff writes that when King Laman2 and his numerous hosts came to do battle with him and his people, he was only 30 years old.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2245",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:10",
    "question": "King Laman himself, even in his old age, did go up to battle against the Lamanites in the strength of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2246",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:11",
    "question": "King Zeniff said that the Lamanites knew nothing concerning the_____, nor the strength of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2247",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:11",
    "question": "King Zeniff wrote that the Lamanites were a strong people, as to the strength of_____.",
    "answer": ["Men"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2248",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:12",
    "question": "The Lamanites were a_____, and ferocious, and a blood-thirsty people, believing in the traditions of their fathers.",
    "answer": ["Wild"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2249",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:12",
    "question": "The Lamanites believed in the traditions of their fathers; which is this-believing that they were driven out of the land of Jerusalem because of the iniquities of their fathers",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2250",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos10:12",
    "question": "The Lamanites believed they were _____ in the wilderness by their brethren.",
    "answer": ["Wronged"],
    "options": ["Wronged", "Taken Advantage", "Left To Wonder"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2251",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:12",
    "question": "The Lamanites also believed they were wronged while crossing the sea; to get to the Promised Land.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2252",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:13",
    "question": "The Lamanites believed they were wronged by their brethren while in the land of their_____ inheritance, after they had crossed the sea.",
    "answer": ["First"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2253",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:13",
    "question": "Zeniff wrote that Nephi was more faithful in keeping the commandments of the Lord; therefore he was favored of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2254",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:13",
    "question": "Zeniff wrote that the Lord heard _____ prayers and answered them.",
    "answer": ["Nephi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2255",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:13",
    "question": "Who did Zeniff say, took the lead of Lehi’s party in their journey in the wilderness?",
    "answer": ["Nephi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2256",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:14",
    "question": "Laman and _____ were wroth with Nephi because they did not understand the dealings of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["Lemuel"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2257",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos10:14",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel were also wroth with Nephi upon the waters because they hardened their_____ against the Lord.",
    "answer": ["Hearts"],
    "options": ["Head", "Hearts", "Minds"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2258",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:15",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel were wroth with Nephi: because after they had arrived in the promise land; he had taken the ruling of the people out of their hands, and they sought to kill him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2259",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:16",
    "question": "Nephi’s older brothers were wroth with him because he had departed into the wilderness as the Lord had commanded him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2260",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:16",
    "question": "Nephi’s older brothers were wroth with him because he took the records which were engraven on the_____ of brass, for they said that he had robbed them.",
    "answer": ["Plates"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2261",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos10:17",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel had taught their children that they should hate the people of Nephi, and should_____ them.",
    "answer": ["Murder"],
    "options": ["Scalp", "Behead", "Murder"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2262",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:17",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel had also taught their children that they should hate the Nephites, and they should murder, and they should plunder them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2263",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:17",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel did not teach their children that they should plunder the Nephites.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2264",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:17",
    "question": "The Lamanites were taught to do all they could to destroy the Nephites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2265",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos10:17",
    "question": "Because of the things that Laman and Lemuel taught the Nephites; their children have an_____ hatred toward the children of Nephi.",
    "answer": ["Eternal"],
    "options": ["Everlasting", "Eternal", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2266",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:18",
    "question": "King Zeniff said that King Laman1 had deceived him by his cunning and lying craft1ness, and his fair promises.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2267",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:19",
    "question": "After King Zeniff told his people about why the Lamanites hated the Nephites and other things, he stimulated his people to go to battle with all their might against the_____.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2268",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos10:19",
    "question": "King Zeniff and his people put their trust in the_____; therefore, they did contend with the Lamanites face to face.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2269",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Zeniff and his people slaughtered so many of the Lamanites that they did not number them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2270",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:22",
    "question": "When King Zeniff began to be old, he did confer the Kingdom upon one of his daughters.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2271",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:1",
    "question": "King Zeniff conferred the kingdom to one of his sons; and his name was_____.",
    "answer": ["Noah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2272",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:1",
    "question": "Noah began to reign in the stead of his father; and he did not walk in the ways of his father.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2273",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:2",
    "question": "For Behold, Noah did not keep the commandments of God, but he did walk after the desires of his_____.",
    "answer": ["Heart"],
    "options": ["Mistress", "Heart", "Eyes"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2274",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:2",
    "question": "King Noah had many wives and_____.",
    "answer": ["Concub1nes"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2275",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:2",
    "question": "King Noah caused his people to commit_____, and do that which was abominable in the sight of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["Sin"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2276",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:2",
    "question": "King Noah’s people committed whoredoms and all manner of wickedness.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2277",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos10:3",
    "question": "King Noah laid a tax of one fifth part of all the Nephites possessed, such as; gold, silver, copper, and brass.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2278",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:3",
    "question": "King Noah did not tax the people of one fifth part of all the iron, fatlings, and grain they possessed because he did not feel that it was worth it.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2279",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:4",
    "question": "The purpose that King Noah taxed the Nephites was so that he could support his_____ and concub1nes.",
    "answer": ["Wives"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2280",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:4",
    "question": "King Noah had to also support his priests, and their wives and concub1nes.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2281",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:4",
    "question": "King Noah changed the affairs of the kingdom by doing all the wicked things that he did.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2282",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:5",
    "question": "King Noah put down all the_____ that had been consecrated by his father, and consecrated new ones in their stead.",
    "answer": ["Priests"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2283",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:5",
    "question": "King Noah consecrated priests that were lifted up in the pride of their hearts.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2284",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:6",
    "question": "King Noah and his priests were supported in their_____.",
    "answer": ["Laz1ness"],
    "options": ["Laz1ness", "Welfare", "Workings"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2285",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:6",
    "question": "King Noah and his priests were also supported by the people in their idolatry and their whoredoms.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2286",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:6",
    "question": "King Noah and his priests were supported by the taxes he put on the people and the people did labor exceedingly to support_____.",
    "answer": ["Iniquity"],
    "options": ["Whoredoms", "Laz1ness", "Iniquity"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2287",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:7",
    "question": "The Nephites became an idolatrous people, because they were deceived by the vain and flattering words of the king and his priests.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2288",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:7",
    "question": "King Noah and his priests spoke flattering things to the Nephites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2289",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah built many elegant and spacious_____.",
    "answer": ["Buildings"],
    "options": ["Warehouses", "Houses", "Buildings"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2290",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:8",
    "question": "King Noah built many elegant and spacious building and ornamented them with f1ne work of wood.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2291",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:8",
    "question": "The buildings that King Noah built were made of precious things, of _____, and of silver, and of brass.",
    "answer": ["Gold"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2292",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:8",
    "question": "King Noah built elegant buildings that were also made of iron, and of copper, and_____.",
    "answer": ["Ziff"],
    "options": ["Titanium", "Platinum", "Ziff"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2293",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:8",
    "question": "In the Book of Mormon we are told that Ziff is a type of metal.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2294",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:3,8",
    "question": "In the Book of Mormon we are never told what Ziff is or if it is a type of metal.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2295",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:9",
    "question": "King Noah built him a spacious _____, and a throne in the midst thereof, all which was of f1ne wood.",
    "answer": ["Palace"],
    "options": ["Palace", "Building", "House"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2296",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:9",
    "question": "The palace that King Noah built with a throne was ornamented with gold and silver and_____ things.",
    "answer": ["Precious"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2297",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:10",
    "question": "King Noah caused that his workmen should work all manner of f1ne work within the walls of the_____.",
    "answer": ["Temple"],
    "options": ["Temple", "House", "Building"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2298",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:10",
    "question": "King Noah’s temple walls were made of f1ne wood, and of copper, and of brass.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2299",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:11",
    "question": "The seats of the priests of King Noah were set above all other seats and were ornamented with pure_____.",
    "answer": ["Gold"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2300",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:11",
    "question": "King Noah caused that the seats of the priests be built with a breastwork before them, that they might rest their bodies and their _____.",
    "answer": ["Arms"],
    "options": ["Legs", "Arms", "Heads"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2301",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:11",
    "question": "King Noah caused a breastwork to be built before them, that they may rest their bodies and arms upon while they should speak lying and vain words to his people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2302",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah built a_____ near the temple; yea, a very high tower.",
    "answer": ["Tower"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2303",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:12",
    "question": "King Noah built a very high tower so he could stand upon the top thereof and overlook the land of Shilom, and also the land of Shemlon.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2305",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:12",
    "question": "The land of Shemlon was possessed by the_____.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2306",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:13",
    "question": "King Noah caused that a great tower be built on the hill north of the land of Shilom.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2308",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:14",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah placed his_____ upon his riches.",
    "answer": ["Heart"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2309",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:14",
    "question": "King Noah spent his time in riotous living with his wives and_____.",
    "answer": ["Concub1nes"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2310",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:14",
    "question": "King Noah and his priests did not spend their time in riotous living and with harlots.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2311",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:15",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah planted v1neyards about the land, and w1ne-presses.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2312",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:15",
    "question": "King Noah did not built w1ne-presses for the making of w1ne but for the making of jams.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2313",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:15",
    "question": "King Noah became a_____ and also his people, because he built an abundance of w1ne-presses.",
    "answer": ["W1ne"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2314",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:15",
    "question": "The term or word w1ne-bibber is only used one time in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2315",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:15",
    "question": "The term or word w1ne-bibber is only mentioned one time in the Book of Mormon and it is used to describe King_____ and his people.",
    "answer": ["Noah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2316",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:15",
    "question": "In what Book of Mormon book can we find the word w1ne-bibber used?",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2317",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites began to come upon the people of King Noah.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2318",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:16",
    "question": "The_____ began to slay the people of King Noah in their fields while they were tending their flocks.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites-"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2319",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:18",
    "question": "The Lamanites began to kill the Nephites and drove many of their flocks out of their land; and to exercise their hatred toward them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2320",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:18",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah sent his armies against the Lamanites and they were driven back, therefore the Nephites returned rejoicing in their spoil.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2321",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:19",
    "question": "Because of the great victory against the Lamanites, the Nephites were lifted up in the_____ of their hearts.",
    "answer": ["Pride"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2322",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:19",
    "question": "The Nephites began to boast in their own strength, saying that their fifty could stand against _____ of Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["Thousands"],
    "options": ["Hundreds", "Thousands", "Millions"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2323",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:19",
    "question": "The Nephites did boast, and they did delight in blood, and the shedding of the_____ of their brethren.",
    "answer": ["Blood"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2324",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:19",
    "question": "Because of the wickedness of King Noah and his priests, the Nephites delighted in the shedding of the blood of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2325",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that there was one among the people of King Noah whose name was_____; and he went forth among them, and began to prophesy.",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2326",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:20",
    "question": "The man that was among the people of King Noah that begin to prophesy was not named Abinidi.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2327",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:20",
    "question": "Abinidi was commanded by the_____ to prophesy to the people of King Noah.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2328",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:20",
    "question": "The Lord told Abinidi to tell the people of King Noah that he had seen their abominations.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2329",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:20",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that the Lord had seen their_____ and their whoredoms.",
    "answer": ["Wickedness"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2330",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:20",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that if they did not repent the Lord would visit them in his_____.",
    "answer": ["Anger"],
    "options": ["Temple", "House", "Anger"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2331",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:21",
    "question": "The Lord told Abinidi to tell the people that unless they repented he would deliver them unto the hands of their enemies.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2332",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:21",
    "question": "_____ told the people that if they did not repent, they shall be brought into bondage.",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2333",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:21",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people of King Noah that unless they repented they shall be afflicted by the hand of their_____.",
    "answer": ["Enemies"],
    "options": ["Enemies", "Sisters", "Fathers"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2334",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:22",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that they shall know that I am the Lord their _____.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2335",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11-22",
    "question": "God told Abinidi to tell the people that he was not a jealous God.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2336",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:22",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that God is a jealous God and would visit the iniquities of his people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2337",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:23",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that except this people repent and turn unto the Lord their _____, they shall be brought into bondage.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2338",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:23",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that they needed to repent and turn unto their God, and if they didn’t; none would deliver them out of bondage except him the Almighty God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2339",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:24",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that when they shall cry unto me I will be slow to hear their_____.",
    "answer": ["Cries"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2340",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:24",
    "question": "The Lord told Abinidi to tell the people that he would suffer them to be_____ by their enemies.",
    "answer": ["Smitten"],
    "options": ["Smitten", "Beaten", "Whipped"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2341",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:25",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that they needed to repent in sackcloth and ashes, and cry_____ to the Lord their God.",
    "answer": ["Mightily"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2342",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:25",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that if they did not repent in sackcloth and ashes, and cry mightily unto the Lord, he would not hear their prayers.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2343",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:25",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that he was commanded by the_____ to tell the people that he would not deliver them out of their afflictions and other things if they did not repent.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2344",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:26",
    "question": "After Abinidi told the Nephites of the things the Lord had commanded him to say they and were wroth with him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2345",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:26",
    "question": "Because the people were wroth with Abinidi, they sought to take away his_____.",
    "answer": ["Life"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2346",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:26",
    "question": "The Lord delivered Abinidi, out of the hands of the people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2347",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:27",
    "question": "When King_____ had heard of the words which Abinidi had spoken unto the people, he was also wroth.",
    "answer": ["Noah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2348",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:27",
    "question": "King Noah said: “Who is_____, that I and my people should be judged of him”?",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2349",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:27",
    "question": "King Noah also said: “Who is the Lord; that shall bring upon my people such great afflictions”",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2350",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:28",
    "question": "King Noah commanded the_____ to bring Abinidi to him so that he could slay him.",
    "answer": ["Nephites"],
    "options": ["Zoramites", "Lamanites", "Nephites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2351",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:28",
    "question": "King Noah said that Abinidi had said things to the Nephites to stir up his people to anger one with the other.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2352",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:28",
    "question": "King Noah said that Abinidi had said things to raise contentions among his people; therefore I will_____ him.",
    "answer": ["Slay"],
    "options": ["Fry", "Slay", "Hang"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2353",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:29",
    "question": "The eyes of the people were not blinded, therefore they did not hardened their hearts against the words of Abinidi.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2354",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:29",
    "question": "King Noah hardened his_____ against the word of the Lord, and he did not repent of his evil doings.",
    "answer": ["Heart"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2355",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos11:29",
    "question": "King Noah did not harden his heart against the words of Abinidi and the Lord; therefore he did repent of his wickedness.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2356",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that after the space of two years that Abinidi came among the people in_____.",
    "answer": ["Disguise"],
    "options": ["A Costume", "Disguise", "Raggedy Clothes"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2357",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:1",
    "question": "Abinidi came in a disguise among the people and began to prophesy among them and they did not recognize him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2358",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:1",
    "question": "The Lord told _____ to prophesy to the people again because they had hardened their hearts against his words.",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2359",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:1",
    "question": "The Lord told Abinidi to prophesy to the Nephites that if they did not repent of their evil doings; he would visit them in his anger.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2360",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:1",
    "question": "The Lord told Abinidi to prophesy to the people that he would not visit them in his fierce anger, and in their iniquities and abominations.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2361",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:2",
    "question": "The Lord told Abinidi to stretch forth his_____ and prophesy to the Nephites: thus saith the Lord, it shall come to pass that this generation, because of their iniquities shall be brought into bondage.",
    "answer": ["Hand"],
    "options": ["Hand", "Arm", "Body"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2362",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:2",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that they shall be smitten on the cheek; yea, and shall be driven by men.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2363",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:2",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that they would be slain; and the_____ of the air, and the dogs, and the wild beast, shall devour their flesh.",
    "answer": ["Vultures"],
    "options": ["Eagles", "Hawks", "Vultures"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2364",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:2",
    "question": "What kind of birds of prey did Abinidi tell the Nephites would devour their flesh if they did not repent?",
    "answer": ["Vultures"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2365",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:3",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that the life of King Noah shall be valued even as a garment in a_____ furnace.",
    "answer": ["Hot"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2366",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:3",
    "question": "Abinidi prophesied that the life of King Noah shall be valued even as a garment in a hot furnace and that he would know the Lord is God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2367",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:4",
    "question": "And if shall come to pass that the Lord will smite the people with fam1ne and_____.",
    "answer": ["Pestilence"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2368",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:4",
    "question": "Because of the fam1ne and pestilence brought upon by the Lord; the people will howl all day long.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2369",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:5",
    "question": "The Lord will cause that the people of King Noah have burdens lashed upon their_____; and they shall be driven like a dumb ass.",
    "answer": ["Backs"],
    "options": ["Shoulders", "Backs", "Chests"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2370",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:6",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that the Lord will send forth hail among the Nephites and it shall smite them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2371",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:6",
    "question": "What kind of direction of the wind that the Lord say he would send to the people of King Noah?",
    "answer": ["East"],
    "options": ["East", "West", "North"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2372",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:6",
    "question": "The Lord said that the Nephites will be smitten with the east wind; and insects will pester their land and devour their grain.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2373",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:7",
    "question": "The Nephites will be smitten with a great pestilence-and this the Lord would do because of their_____ and abominations.",
    "answer": ["Iniquities"],
    "options": ["Iniquities", "Laz1ness", "Wickedness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2374",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:8",
    "question": "The Lord said that if the Nephites did not repent he would utterly destroy them from the_____ of the earth.",
    "answer": ["Face"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2375",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:8",
    "question": "Abinidi testified that King Noah and his people would leave a record behind and that the Lord would preserve it.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2376",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:8",
    "question": "The record that King Noah and his people would leave behind shall be possessed by other nations which shall possess the land.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2377",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:8",
    "question": "The purpose that the Lord wanted to preserve the record is so that he could discover the abominations of King Noah’s people to other nations which shall possess the land.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2378",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:8",
    "question": "King Zeniff wrote all of the prophesies that Abinidi said to the people of King Noah and they are written in the Book of Mosiah chapter #12.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2379",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people were angry with Abinidi and carried and bound him before King_____.",
    "answer": ["Noah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2380",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:9",
    "question": "The people told King Noah that Abinidi prophesied evil concerning his people, and said that God would destroy them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2381",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:10",
    "question": "The Nephites told King Noah that Abinidi had prophesied evil concerning his life and said that it would be as valued as a garment in a_____ of fire.",
    "answer": ["Furnace"],
    "options": ["Pit", "Blaze", "Furnace"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2382",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:11",
    "question": "The people told King Noah that Abinidi had also prophesied that his life would be as a stalk, even as a dry stalk of the field, which is run over by the beasts and trodden under foot.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2383",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:12",
    "question": "The Nephites said that Abinidi had said that King Noah shall be as the blossoms of a thistle, which, when it is fully ripened and the wind blows, it is driven forth upon the face of the land.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2384",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:12",
    "question": "The people of King Noah said that Abinidi had prophesied all things unto them and said that he pretended that the Lord had spoken it.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2385",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:12",
    "question": "The Nephites told King Noah that_____ said that unless he repented; bad things would come upon the people and King Noah because of their iniquities.",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2386",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:13",
    "question": "The people asked King Noah:  “O king, what great evil have you done, or what great sins have we committed, that we should be condemned of God or judged of this_____”?",
    "answer": ["Man"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2387",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:14",
    "question": "The people told King Noah that he was guiltless, and had not sinned; therefore, this man has lied concerning him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2388",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:14",
    "question": "The people told King Noah that because he had not sinned, _____ had prophesied in vain.",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2389",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:15",
    "question": "And behold, we are strong, we shall not come into_____, or be taken captive by our enemies.",
    "answer": ["Bondage"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2390",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:16",
    "question": "The people delivered Abinidi into the hands of King Noah and told him to do with him as he seemed fit.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2391",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:17",
    "question": "And if came to pass that King Noah caused that Abinidi should be cast into_____.",
    "answer": ["Prison"],
    "options": ["A Dungeon", "A Pit", "Prison"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2392",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:17",
    "question": "King Noah commanded that his_____ gather together that he might hold a counsel with them concerning what they should do with Abinidi.",
    "answer": ["Priests"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2393",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:18",
    "question": "And it came to pass that they said unto King Noah: Bring him to us that we may question him; and the king_____ that he should be brought before them.",
    "answer": ["Commanded"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2394",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:19",
    "question": "The priests of King Noah began to question Abinidi that they might cross him that thereby they might have wherewith to accuse him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2395",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:19",
    "question": "Abinidi answered the questions of King Noah’s priests boldly, and withstood all their questions.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2396",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:12",
    "question": "To the astonishment of the priests of King Noah, Abinidi did withstand them in all their questions and confounded them in all their_____.",
    "answer": ["Words"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2397",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that one of the priest of King Noah asked Abinidi to interpret some words that were written by their fathers and what was the meaning of them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2398",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:24",
    "question": "Some of the words that the priests of King Noah said were these: The Lord has made bare his_____ arm in the eyes of all the nations, and all the ends of the earth shall see the salvation of God.",
    "answer": ["Holy"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2399",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:25",
    "question": "Abinidi replied to them by saying unto them:”Are you priests pretend to teach this people, and to understand the spirit of prophesying, and yet desire to know of me what these things mean”?",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2400",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:26",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah:  Woe, be unto you for perverting the ways of the Lord! For if ye understand these things ye have not taught them; therefore, ye have perverted the ways of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2401",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos12:27",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests that they had not applied their hearts to understanding; therefore, they had not been_____.",
    "answer": ["Wise"],
    "options": ["Wise", "Enlightened", "Useful"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2402",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:27",
    "question": "Abinidi asked the priests of King Noah: “What do you teach the people”?",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2403",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:28",
    "question": "The priest of King Noah told Abinidi that they taught the people the Law of_____.",
    "answer": ["Moses"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2404",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:29",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah if they taught the Law of Moses; why do you not keep it?",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2405",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:29",
    "question": "Abinidi asked the priests of King Noah: Why they set their_____ upon riches?",
    "answer": ["Hearts"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2406",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:29",
    "question": "Abinidi asked the priests of King Noah why they commit whoredoms and spend their strength with harlots?",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2407",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:30",
    "question": "Abinidi knew that the priests of King Noah knew that the things he had spoken to them were true.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2408",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:31",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that you will be_____ for your iniquities, for you have said that you teach the Law of Moses.",
    "answer": ["Smitten"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2409",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:31-32",
    "question": "Abinidi asked the priests of King Noah:  Does salvation come by the Law of Moses?  And they answered and said that salvation did come by the Law of_____.",
    "answer": ["Moses"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2410",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:33",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah that he knew if they kept the commandments of God they would be saved.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2411",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos12:33",
    "question": "On what mountain did Abinidi say that the Lord delivered the commandments unto Moses?",
    "answer": ["Sinai"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2412",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:35-36",
    "question": "Abinidi recited part of the Ten Commandments to the priests of King Noah.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2413",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:37",
    "question": "According to Abinidi, King Noah and his people kept the Law of Moses.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2414",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:33-37",
    "question": "Abinidi was inspired to say the things he did because of the words of the five books of Moses.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2415",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:33-37",
    "question": "Abinidi testified to King Noah and his priests that there are actually six books of Moses and that the sixth book is lost unto the children of men.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2416",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:2",
    "question": "King Noah’s priests stood forward and attempted to lay their hands on Abinidi; but he withstood them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2417",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:3",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah that if they were to touch him and lay their hands upon him, the_____ would smite them.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2418",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos13:4",
    "question": "The priests of King Noah could not do a thing to Abinidi because he had not finished delivering the_____ that the Lord wanted him to deliver.",
    "answer": ["Message"],
    "options": ["Package", "Handbag", "Message"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2419",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:4",
    "question": "Because Abinidi told and spoke the things the Lord had commanded him to say and had told them the truth; the priests of King Noah were angry with him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2420",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos13:4",
    "question": "Because Abinidi spoke the word of God, the priests judged him to be _____.",
    "answer": ["Mad"],
    "options": ["Terrible", "Mad", "Crazy"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2421",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:5",
    "question": "The people of King Noah did not dare to lay their hands upon Abinidi because the_____ of the Lord which was upon him.",
    "answer": ["Spirit"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2422",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:5",
    "question": "The face of Abinidi shone with exceeding luster, even as_____, did while in the mount of Sinai, while speaking with the Lord.",
    "answer": ["Moses"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2423",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:33&13:5",
    "question": "Mount Sinai is spoken of only in the Book of Mosiah.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2424",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos13:6",
    "question": "Abinidi spoke with the power and_____ from God.",
    "answer": ["Authority"],
    "options": ["F1nesse", "Likeness", "Authority"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2425",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:7",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that they had no power to slay him; therefore, he would finish his message.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2426",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:7",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people of King Noah that he perceived that his message cuts them to their_____, because he told them the truth concerning their iniquities.",
    "answer": ["Hearts"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2427",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:8",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that his words did not fill them with wonder and amazement, and with anger.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2428",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:9",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people of King Noah that it did not matter where he went after he finished his message, if it so be that he would he saved.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2429",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:10",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people: “What you do with me, after this, shall be as a type and a_____ of the things which are to come”.",
    "answer": ["Shadow"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2430",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos13:11",
    "question": "Abinidi perceived that the commandments of_____ were not written in their hearts.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["Moses", "God", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2431",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:11",
    "question": "Abinidi perceived that the Nephites had studied and taught iniquity for the most part of their lives.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2432",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:12-24",
    "question": "Abinidi read unto the people of King Noah the remainder of the ten commandments of God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2433",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos12:35&13:12-24",
    "question": "The Ten Commandment of God are never written or recited by anyone in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2434",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:25",
    "question": "After Abinidi had finished speaking: he asked the priests of King Noah if they had taught the people to observe the commandments and to keep them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2435",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos13:26",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah that if they had taught and observe the commandments of God; the Lord would not have caused him to come forth and to prophesy_____ concerning them.",
    "answer": ["Evil"],
    "options": ["Evil", "Destruction", "Calamities"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2436",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:27",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that it was expedient for them to keep the Law of Moses as of yet; but that it would come a time when it shall no more be expedient to keep the_____ of Moses.",
    "answer": ["Law"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2437",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:28",
    "question": "Abinidi told the people that salvation does not come by the Law of Moses alone.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2438",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:28",
    "question": "Abinidi said that if it were not for the atonement, which God himself shall make for the sins and iniquities of his people; that they most unavoidably perish, not withstanding the Law of Moses.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2439",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos13:29",
    "question": "And now I say unto you that it is expedient that there should be a law given to the children of _____.",
    "answer": ["Israel"],
    "options": ["Nephi", "Lehi", "Israel"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2440",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:29",
    "question": "According to Abinidi the Law of Moses was not very strict or hard to live.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2441",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:29",
    "question": "The purpose the Law of Moses was given to the children of Israel because they were a stiffnecked people, quick to do iniquity, and slow to_____ their God.",
    "answer": ["Remember"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2442",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:30",
    "question": "The Law of Moses was a law of performances and of ordinances, a law which they were to observe strictly from day to day.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2443",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:30",
    "question": "The Law of Moses was also given to the children of_____ to keep them in remembrance of God and their duty to him.",
    "answer": ["Israel"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2444",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:31",
    "question": "Abinidi said that the Law of Moses and all the other things were types of things to come.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2445",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos13:32",
    "question": "The children of Israel did not understand the Law of Moses because of the hardness of their_____.",
    "answer": ["Hearts"],
    "options": ["Arteries", "Minds", "Hearts"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2446",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:32",
    "question": "The children of Israel could not understand that there could not any man be saved except it were through the redemption of_____.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2447",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:33",
    "question": "Abinidi said: “Did not Moses prophesy unto them concerning the coming of the Messiah”?",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2448",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:33",
    "question": "Abinidi said that all the prophets more or less have prophesied concerning the Messiah and of other things since the world began.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2449",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos13:34",
    "question": "The prophets have prophesied and said that_____ himself should come down among the children of men, and take upon him the form of a man.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2450",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:34",
    "question": "The prophets have also prophesied that God himself shall go forth in mighty power upon the face of the earth.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2451",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos13:35",
    "question": "Abinidi said:  Have not the prophets also said that he should bring to pass the resurrection of the dead, and that he, himself, should be oppressed and afflicted?",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2452",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos14:1",
    "question": "In chapter #14 what Old Testament prophet does Abinidi quote to the priests of King Noah?",
    "answer": ["Isaiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2453",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos14:3",
    "question": "Abinidi said told the priests of King Noah that the Lord he will be despised and rejected of men.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2454",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos14:5",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests that Jesus Christ was wounded for our transgressions, he was bruised for our_____.",
    "answer": ["Iniquities"],
    "options": ["Iniquities", "Mistakes", "Shortcomings"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2455",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos14:5",
    "question": "Abinidi also told the priests of King Noah that the chastisement of our peace was upon Jesus Christ; and with his stripes we are_____.",
    "answer": ["Healed"],
    "options": ["Made Clean", "Made Whole", "Healed"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2456",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos14:6",
    "question": "Abinidi said “All men are like sheep, have gone astray; we have turned every one to his own way; and the Lord hath laid on him the iniquities of us all”.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2457",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos14:7",
    "question": "He was oppressed, and he was afflicted, yet he opened not his_____.",
    "answer": ["Mouth"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2458",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos14:7",
    "question": "He is brought as a lamb to the slaughter; and as a sheep before her_____ is dumb so he opened not his mouth.",
    "answer": ["Shearers"],
    "options": ["Master", "Shepherd", "Shearers"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2459",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos14:8",
    "question": "Abinidi quoted the prophet Isaiah when he said: “For he was cut off out of the land of the living; for the transgressions of my people was he stricken”.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2460",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos14:9",
    "question": "And he made his grave with the wicked; and with the rich in his death; because he had done no_____, neither was any deceit in his mouth.",
    "answer": ["Evil"],
    "options": ["Good", "Harm", "Evil"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2461",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos14:10",
    "question": "Abinidi said that it did not please the Lord to bruise him; yet he has put him to grief.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2462",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos14:10",
    "question": "When thou shall make him his soul an offering for sin he shall see his seed, he shall prolong his days and the pleasure of the Lord shall prosper in his hand.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2463",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos14:11",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King _____:  He shall see the travail of his soul, and shall be satisfied.",
    "answer": ["Noah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2464",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos14:11",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests: By his knowledge shall my righteous servant justify many; for he shall bear their iniquities.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2465",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos14:12",
    "question": "Therefore will I divide him a portion with the great, and he shall divide the spoil with the_____, because he has poured out his soul unto death.",
    "answer": ["Strong"],
    "options": ["Poor", "Strong", "Weak"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2466",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos14:12",
    "question": "Abinidi said that Jesus Christ was numbered with the transgressors; and he bore the sins of many, and made intercessions for the transgressors.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2467",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:1",
    "question": "Abinidi tell the priests of King Noah I would that you should understand that_____ himself shall come down among the children of men, and shall redeem his people.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2468",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:1",
    "question": "Because God will dwell in the_____ he shall be called the Son of God.",
    "answer": ["Flesh"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2469",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos152",
    "question": "Because God will subjected his flesh to the will of the Father, he will be the Father and the Son",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2470",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:3",
    "question": "Abinidi said that he will be the Father because he was conceived by the power of God; and the Son, because of the flesh; thus becoming the Father and the_____.",
    "answer": ["Son"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2471",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:4",
    "question": "Abinidi said that Jesus Christ and God are one God, yea, the very Eternal Father of heaven and of the earth.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2472",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos15:5",
    "question": "And thus the flesh becoming subject to the Spirit, or the Son to the Father, being one God, suffering temptation, and not yielding to_____.",
    "answer": ["Temptation"],
    "options": ["Temptation", "His Will", "Sin"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2473",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:5",
    "question": "Jesus Christ will suffer himself to be mocked, and scourged, and cast out, and will not be disowned by his people.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2474",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:6",
    "question": "Jesus Christ will work mighty miracles among the children of men; yet he shall be led, even as Isaiah said, as a_____ before the shearer is dumb, so he opened not his mouth.",
    "answer": ["Sheep"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2475",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:7",
    "question": "Abinidi said: Jesus Christ shall be led, crucified, and be slain, the flesh becoming subjected even unto death, the will of the Son being swallowed up in the will of the Father.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2476",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:8",
    "question": "Abinidi said one of the most important statements about the atonement of Jesus Christ when he said: “Thus God breaketh the_____ of death, having ga1ned the victory over death, giving the Son power to make intercession for the children of men”.",
    "answer": ["Bands"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2477",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:9",
    "question": "Abinidi said that Jesus Christ will have ascended into heaven, having the bowels of mercy; being filled with compassion towards the children of_____.",
    "answer": ["Men"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2478",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:9",
    "question": "Jesus Christ will stand between the children of men and justice; having broken the bands of death.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2479",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:9",
    "question": "Because Jesus Christ will break the bands of death he will take upon himself the iniquities and transgressions of the children of men, having redeemed them and satisfied the demands of_____.",
    "answer": ["Justice"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2480",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:10",
    "question": "Abinidi said: When the soul of Jesus Christ has been made an offering for sin he shall see his seed.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2481",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:11",
    "question": "Abinidi said that whosoever has heard the words of the holy prophets who have prophesied concerning the coming of the Lord and have kept his Commandments; look forward to the remission of their sins.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2482",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:11",
    "question": "Those that have hearkened into the words of the prophets and believed that the Lord would redeem his people, and have looked forward to the remission of their sins are heirs of the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2483",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:12",
    "question": "The people whose sins Jesus Christ has borne; these are they for whom he has died to redeem them from transgressions are his seed.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2484",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos15:13",
    "question": "Abinidi said that all the_____ who have opened their mouths since the world began and have not fallen into transgression are also his seed.",
    "answer": ["Prophets"],
    "options": ["People", "Tribes", "Prophets"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2485",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:14",
    "question": "The prophets of the Lord have published peace, who have brought good tidings of good, who have published salvation: and said unto Zion: Thy God reigns are also the seed of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2486",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos15:16",
    "question": "“O how beautiful upon the mountains are the_____ of those who are still publishing peace”!",
    "answer": ["Feet"],
    "options": ["Legs", "Arms", "Feet"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2487",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:18",
    "question": "Abinidi said that the Lord is the founder of peace, and it is he who has redeemed his people and granted salvation unto his people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2488",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos15:19",
    "question": "The redemption of Jesus Christ was prepared from the_____ of the world.",
    "answer": ["Start"],
    "options": ["Start", "Ending"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2489",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:19",
    "question": "If it was not for the redemption of Jesus Christ that he has made for his people, all mankind must perish.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2490",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:20",
    "question": "Because Jesus Christ broke the bands of death and he reigns and has the power over the dead, he brings to pass the resurrection of the_____.",
    "answer": ["Dead"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2491",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:21",
    "question": "All those that died before the resurrection of Jesus Christ, will not be a part of the first resurrection.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2492",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:23",
    "question": "Those people who have believed in the words of the prophets and have kept the commandments of God will dwell with God who has raised them and have eternal life through Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2493",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:24",
    "question": "Those who have died before Jesus Christ came to earth and have come in their ignorance, not having salvation declared unto them; the Lord will bring about the restoration to them and are a part of the first resurrection.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2494",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:25",
    "question": "Abinidi said that little children that have died before Jesus Christ came to the earth have no eternal life.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2495",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos15:26",
    "question": "Abinidi said those who willingly rebel against God and have known of his commandments and did not keep them have no part in the_____ resurrection.",
    "answer": ["1st"],
    "options": ["1st", "2nd", "3rd"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2496",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos15:27",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah that the Lord cannot deny himself; for he cannot deny justice when it has its claim.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2497",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos15:28",
    "question": "Abinidi said that the time shall come that the salvation of the Lord shall be declared to every_____, kindred, tongue and people.",
    "answer": ["Nation"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2498",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos15:29",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests that the watchmen shall lift up their voices together and sing; for they shall see eye to eye, when the Lord shall bring again_____.",
    "answer": ["Zion"],
    "options": ["Jews", "The Nephites", "Zion"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2499",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos15:31",
    "question": "The Lord has made bare his holy arm in the eyes of all nations; and all the ends of the earth shall see the_____ of our God.",
    "answer": ["Salvation"],
    "options": ["Salvation", "Mercy", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2500",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Abinidi said the time shall come when all shall see the salvation of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2501",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:1",
    "question": "Not only will every nation, kindred, tongue, and people see the salvation of the Lord but they shall also see_____ to eye and shall confess before God that his judgments are just.",
    "answer": ["Eye"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2502",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:2",
    "question": "The wicked shall be cast out, and they shall have cause to howl, weep and wail, and gnash their_____.",
    "answer": ["Teeth"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2503",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos16:2",
    "question": "The wicked will be cast out because they would not hearken unto the _____ of the Lord; therefore, the Lord will not redeem them.",
    "answer": ["Voice"],
    "options": ["Teachings", "Voice", "Principles"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2504",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:3",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah that men are carnal and devilish and the devil has power over them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2505",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:3",
    "question": "Abinidi said that the old serpent beguiled our first parents, which was the cause of their fall.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2506",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:3",
    "question": "Abinidi mentions our first parents by name.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2507",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:3",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests that the fall caused that all mankind become carnal, sensual, and devilish, knowing evil from_____; subjecting themselves to the devil.",
    "answer": ["Good"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2508",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos16:4",
    "question": "Who redeemed his people from their lost and fallen state?",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["Moses", "God", "Adam"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2509",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:4",
    "question": "All mankind were lost, and they would have been endlessly lost were it not that God redeemed his people from their lost and fallen state.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2510",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:5",
    "question": "Abinidi said that we should remember that he that persists in his own carnal nature, and goes on in the ways of sin and rebellion against God, remains in his fallen state.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2511",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:5",
    "question": "Abinidi said that those that remain in their fallen state; that the devil has power over them, therefore, it is though there was no redemption made, being an enemy to_____.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2512",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:5",
    "question": "What is the name of the person that is an enemy to God and will always be forever and forever?",
    "answer": ["Devil", "Satan", "Adversary"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2513",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:6",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah that if Christ had not come into the world, speaking of things to come as though they have already come, there could have been no redemption.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2514",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:7",
    "question": "And if Jesus Christ had not risen from the dead, and broke the bands of death the grave should have no victory or sting, therefore, there could have been no resurrection.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2515",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:8",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests that there is a resurrection therefore the grave has no victory, and the sting of death is swallowed up in_____.",
    "answer": ["Christ"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2516",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:9",
    "question": "Who did Abinidi say is the light and the life of the world?",
    "answer": ["Jesus"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2517",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos16:9",
    "question": "Jesus Christ is the light that is endless, that can never be_____.",
    "answer": ["Darkened"],
    "options": ["Put Out", "Darkened", "Shutoff"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2518",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:9",
    "question": "Jesus Christ is not only an endless light but also a life which is endless that there can be no death.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2519",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:10",
    "question": "Abinidi said that even this mortal body shall put on immorality, and this corruption shall put on_____.",
    "answer": ["Incorruption"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2520",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:10",
    "question": "Abinidi tells the priests of King Noah and us that will shall be brought before the judgment bar of God to be judged.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2521",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:10",
    "question": "Abinidi tell us that we shall be judged according to or works whether they be good or whether they be_____.",
    "answer": ["Evil"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2522",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:11",
    "question": "If our works are good we will go to the resurrection of endless life and happiness; and if they be evil, to the resurrection of endless damnation.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2523",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:11",
    "question": "If our works are evil we will go to the resurrection of endless damnation, being delivered up to the_____, who has subjected us, which is damnation----",
    "answer": ["Devil"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2524",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:12",
    "question": "Because the devil has subjected us to damnation; we will have gone according to our own carnal wills and desires having never called upon the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2525",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:12",
    "question": "The Lord will always have his arms of mercy extended to us, if we call upon him and are faithful in keeping his _____.",
    "answer": ["Commandments"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2526",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:12",
    "question": "The Lord had his arms of mercy extended to the Nephites and they would not call upon him; and they were warned of their iniquities and yet they would not depart from them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2527",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:12",
    "question": "Abinidi said that the people were commanded to_____ and yet they would not repent.",
    "answer": ["Repent"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2528",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:13",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah that they should tremble and remember that only in and through Christ can they be saved.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2529",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos16:14",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests that if they teach the Law of_____, also teach that it is a shadow of those things which are to come.",
    "answer": ["Moses"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2530",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos16:14",
    "question": "Abinidi did not tell the priests of King Noah that if they teach to the Law of Moses; also teach that it is not a shadow of those things which are to come.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2531",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos16:15",
    "question": "Abinidi also told the priests of King Noah to teach to the people that redemption comes through Christ the Lord, who is the very_____ Father.",
    "answer": ["Eternal"],
    "options": ["Good", "Eternal", "Busy"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2532",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:1",
    "question": "When Abinidi finished saying the things that he said to the priest; King Noah commanded that the_____ should take him and cause that he should be put to death.",
    "answer": ["Priests"],
    "options": ["Priests", "People", "Nephites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2533",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:2",
    "question": "Which one of the priests of King Noah believed in the words of Abinidi?",
    "answer": ["Alma1"],
    "options": ["Amulon", "Gadianton", "Alma1"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2534",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos17:2",
    "question": "What Book of Mormon record keeper and prophet was Alma1 descendant of?",
    "answer": ["Nephi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2535",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:2",
    "question": "When Alma1 first heard and believed the words of Abinidi he was in his fifty’s.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2536",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:2",
    "question": "Alma1 believed the words that Abinidi spoken, for he knew of the iniquity which he had testified against them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2537",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos17:2",
    "question": "Who began to plead with King Noah not to be angry with Abinidi, but that he might depart in peace?",
    "answer": ["Alma"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2538",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:3",
    "question": "Because of the things that Alma1 said King Noah was more wroth, and caused that he should be_____ out from among them.",
    "answer": ["Cast"],
    "options": ["Delivered", "Cast", "Taken"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2539",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:3",
    "question": "King Noah sent his servants after Alma1 that they might slay him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2540",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:4",
    "question": "Alma1 fled from the king’s servants and they could not find him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2541",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:4",
    "question": "What is the name of the person that wrote all the words which Abinidi had spoken?",
    "answer": ["Alma1"],
    "options": ["Nephi", "Laman", "Alma1"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2542",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos17:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah had his Guards surround_____ and take him; and they bound him and cast him into prison.",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2543",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:6",
    "question": "How many days did King Noah hold council with his priests, and caused that Abinidi, be brought before him?",
    "answer": ["3"],
    "options": ["1", "Or", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2544",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:7",
    "question": "King Noah told Abinidi that they had found an accusation against him and that he was worthy of_____.",
    "answer": ["Death"],
    "options": ["Hanging", "Money", "Death"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2545",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:8",
    "question": "The main reason Abinidi was put to death was because he said that God himself should come down in the flesh among the children of men",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2546",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos17:8",
    "question": "King Noah wanted_____ to recall the words he said to him and his people.",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2547",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:8",
    "question": "King Noah wanted Abinidi to not recall the words he had said and said that he had spoken evil concerning him and his people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2548",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:9",
    "question": "Abinidi said that he would recall the words that he had spoken to King Noah concerning his people.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2549",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:9",
    "question": "Abinidi told King Noah that the words he had spoken to him and his people were_____; and that he may know of their surety because I have suffered myself and have fallen into your hands.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False", "Terrible"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2550",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:10",
    "question": "Abinidi said that he would suffer death rather than recall his words he had spoken to King Noah and his people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2551",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:10",
    "question": "Abinidi said that his words would stand as testimony against King Zoram.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2552",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:10",
    "question": "Abinidi said that he would not recall his words and that his words would stand against a testimony to King Noah.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2553",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:10",
    "question": "Abinidi warned King Noah that if he would slay him, he would be shedding innocent_____, and that it would stand as a testimony against him at the last day.",
    "answer": ["Blood"],
    "options": ["Heart", "Blood", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2554",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:11",
    "question": "King Noah did not want to release Abinidi and he did not fear his words; because he did not fear the judgments of God and that they would come upon him.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2555",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos17:12",
    "question": "The priests lifted up their voices against _____, and began to accuse him of reviling King Noah.",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2556",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:12",
    "question": "King Noah was angry because of the words his priests had said concerning Abinidi, and he delivered him up that he might be slain.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2557",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that they took Abinidi and bound him, and scourged his skin with_____, yea, even unto death.",
    "answer": ["Faggots"],
    "options": ["Gasol1ne", "Kerosene", "Faggots"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2558",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:14",
    "question": "When the flames began to scorch Abinidi, he did not say a word but suffered a horrible death.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2559",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:15",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests of King Noah: “Even as ye have done unto me, so shall it come to pass that thy seed shall cause that many shall suffer even pains of death by fire”.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2560",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:15",
    "question": "Abinidi said that the seed of the priest would suffer the pains of death by fire because they belived in the salvation of the Lord their _____.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["Man", "God", "Leader"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2561",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:16",
    "question": "Abinidi also told the priests that it shall come to pass that they shall be afflicted with all manner of_____ because of their iniquities.",
    "answer": ["Diseases"],
    "options": ["Wars", "Pestilences", "Diseases"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2562",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:17",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests and the people that they shall be smitten on every hand.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2563",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:17",
    "question": "Abinidi also told the priests and the people, that they shall be driven and scattered back and forth, even as a wild flock is driven by wild and ferocious _____.",
    "answer": ["Beasts"],
    "options": ["Lions", "Tigers", "Beasts"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2564",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:18",
    "question": "Abinidi told the priests that they would be hunted and shall be taken by the_____ of their enemies, and then shall they suffer, like he has suffered the pains of death by fire.",
    "answer": ["Hand"],
    "options": ["Neck", "Hand", "Sword"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2565",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:19",
    "question": "God executes vengeance upon those that destroy his people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2566",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:19",
    "question": "The last words Abinidi spoke before he died were: “O God, receive my soul”.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2567",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos17:20",
    "question": "Abinidi suffered the pains of death by what means?",
    "answer": ["Fire"],
    "options": ["Hanging", "Torture", "Fire"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2569",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos17:20",
    "question": "Alma1 wrote that Abinidi was put to death because he would not deny the commandments of God, having sealed the truth of his words by his death.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2570",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma1 the one who had fled from the servants of King Noah, repented of his sins and_____.",
    "answer": ["Iniquities"],
    "options": ["Abomination", "Iniquities", "Wickedness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2571",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:1",
    "question": "Alma1 went about privately among the people and began to teach the people the words of_____.",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2572",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:2",
    "question": "Alma1 taught the people about the power, sufferings, and death of Jesus Christ; and his resurrection and ascension into heaven.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2573",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:3",
    "question": "Alma1 taught the people privately because he did not want King____ to come to the knowledge that he was teaching them.",
    "answer": ["Noah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2574",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:3",
    "question": "Many of the people that Alma1taught did not believe his words.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2575",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:4,8",
    "question": "What is the name of the place where Alma1 taught the people?",
    "answer": ["Mormon"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2576",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:4",
    "question": "The waters of Mormon bordered a land that had been infested, by times or at seasons, by wild beasts.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2577",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:5",
    "question": "At the place called Mormon there was a fountain of pure_____.",
    "answer": ["Water"],
    "options": ["Gold", "Water", "Silver"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2578",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that as many people believed Alma1’s words gathered together at the place called Mormon to hear his words.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2579",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:7",
    "question": "Alma did teach them, and did preach unto them_____, and redemption, and faith on the Lord.",
    "answer": ["Repentance"],
    "options": ["Chastity", "Doctr1ne", "Repentance"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2580",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:8",
    "question": "The people that had gathered at the Waters of Mormon were desirous to come unto the fold of God, and to be called his people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2581",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:8",
    "question": "The people who were with Alma1 were not willing to bear one anothers' burdens, that they might be light.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2582",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:9",
    "question": "The people at the Waters of Mormon were willing to mourn with those that_____; and comfort those that stand in need of comfort.",
    "answer": ["Mourn"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2583",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:9",
    "question": "As disciples of Jesus Christ we must stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all_____.",
    "answer": ["Places"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2584",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:9",
    "question": "As we stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all places; we will be numbered with those of the first resurrection, that we may have eternal life",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2585",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:10",
    "question": "Alma1 asked the people if they were willing to be baptized in the name of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2586",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:10",
    "question": "Alma1 asked to people to be baptized and to witness before him that they would enter a covenant with him, and keep his commandments.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2587",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:10",
    "question": "Alma1 told the people that if they were baptized and keep the Lord’s commandments; he would pour his_____ more abundantly upon them.",
    "answer": ["Spirit"],
    "options": ["Soul", "Heart", "Spirit"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2588",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:11",
    "question": "When the people heard the words of Alma1, they clapped their hands for joy, and exclaimed:  This is the desire of our_____.",
    "answer": ["Hearts"],
    "options": ["Souls", "Hearts", "Heads"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2589",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:12",
    "question": "Who was one of the first persons to be baptized by Alma1 in the Waters of Mormon?",
    "answer": ["Helam"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2591",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:14",
    "question": "Alma1 and Helam were buried in the water and baptized at the same time and arose and came forth out of the water rejoicing, being filled with the Spirit of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2592",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:16,35",
    "question": "All the people that were at the Waters of Mormon with Alma1 were baptized.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2593",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:16",
    "question": "Alma1 baptized 240 souls at the Waters of Mormon and they were filled with the grace of_____.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2594",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:17",
    "question": "The people that Alma1 baptized were called the Church of God, or the Church of Christ, from that time forward.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2595",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:18",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma1, having authority from God, orda1ned priests; even one____ to every fifty of their number.",
    "answer": ["Priest"],
    "options": ["Teacher", "Priest", "Deacon"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2596",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:18",
    "question": "The priests that Alma1 orda1ned were to teach the people concerning the things pertaining to the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2597",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:19",
    "question": "Alma1 commanded the priests to teach nothing except the things which he had taught, and things which had been spoken by the mouth of the holy_____.",
    "answer": ["Prophets"],
    "options": ["Ghost", "Spirit", "Prophets"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2598",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:20",
    "question": "Alma1 did not command the priests to preach nothing save it were repentance and faith in the Lord, who had redeemed his people.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2599",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:21",
    "question": "Alma1 did not command the people that they should get along one with the other and that they should have no contentions among them.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2600",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:21",
    "question": "Alma1 told the people that they should look forward with one eye, having one faith and one_____, having their hearts knit together in unity and love one towards another.",
    "answer": ["Baptism"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2601",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:23",
    "question": "Alma1 commanded the people to observe the _____day, and keep it holy and also to give thanks to the Lord their God every day.",
    "answer": ["Sabbath"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2602",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:24",
    "question": "Alma1 commanded the priests whom he had orda1ned, that they should get paid by the people for their labors and support.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2603",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:25",
    "question": "There was one day of every week that was set apart that they should gather themselves together to teach the people, and to worship the_____ their God.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2604",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:26",
    "question": "The priests were not to depend upon the people for their support; but for their labor they were to receive the grace of God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2605",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:26",
    "question": "The priests by their labor were to receive the grace of God and that they might wax strong in the Spirit, having the knowledge of God; that they might teach with the power and_____ from God.",
    "answer": ["Authority"],
    "options": ["Authority", "Knowledge", "Grace"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2606",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:27",
    "question": "Alma1 commanded the people of the church to impart of their substance, every one according to that which they had; if he had more abundantly he should impart more abundantly.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2607",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:28",
    "question": "The people of the church were to impart of their_____ of their own free will and good desires towards God, and to those priests that stood in need, and to every needy, naked soul.",
    "answer": ["Substance"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2608",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos18:29",
    "question": "The people were commanded of God; and they did walk uprightly before God, imparting to one another both temporally and_____ according to their needs and wants.",
    "answer": ["Spiritually"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2609",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:30",
    "question": "And it came to pass that all things that Alma1 commanded the people to do were done in the Waters or Mormon, in the forest that was near the Waters of Mormon.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2610",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:30",
    "question": "“Oh! How beautiful are they to the eyes of them who come to the knowledge of their Redeemer; and how blessed are they, for they shall sing to his praise forever”.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2611",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:32",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah, having discovered a movement among the people, sent his_____ to watch them.",
    "answer": ["Servants"],
    "options": ["Army", "Troops", "Servants"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2612",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:33",
    "question": "King Noah said that Alma1 was stirring up the people to rebellion against him at the Waters of Mormon; therefore he sent his army to destroy them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2613",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos18:34",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma1 and the people of the Lord were apprised of the coming of the king’s army and departed into the wilderness.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2614",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah’s army found Alma1 and the people of the church and destroyed them.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2615",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:2",
    "question": "And now behold, the forces of the King Noah were big, and there began to be a division among the people.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2616",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:3",
    "question": "The lesser part of the people began to breathe out threats against the king, and there began to be a great contention among them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2617",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos19:4",
    "question": "What was the name of the man who was among the people who was an enemy of King Noah?",
    "answer": ["Gideon"],
    "options": ["Alma1", "Gideon", "Moroni"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2618",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos19:4",
    "question": "Gideon was a strong man and an enemy to King Noah, therefore he drew his_____, and swore in his wrath the he would slay the king.",
    "answer": ["Sword"],
    "options": ["Pistol", "Rifle", "Sword"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2619",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:5",
    "question": "Gideon and King Noah fought each other; and when the king saw that he was about to be overpowered by Gideon, he fled and got upon the tower which was near the temple.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2620",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos19:6",
    "question": "When King Noah was upon the tower he cast his eyes round about towards the land of Shemlon and saw that the armies of the_____ were within the borders of the land.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["Zoramites", "Nephites", "Lamanites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2621",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:7",
    "question": "King Noah cried out:  Gideon, spare me, for the Lamanites are upon us, and they will destroy us and they will destroy my people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2622",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:8",
    "question": "Gideon spared the life of King Noah because the king was more concerned about the people than his own life.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2623",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos19:11",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Noah commanded that all men should leave their wives and their children, and flee before the_____.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2624",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:12",
    "question": "All the men that King Noah commanded to flee before the Lamanites left their wives and children.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2625",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos19:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that some of the men who had tarried with their wives and children caused that their fair_____ should stand forth and plead with the Lamanites that they would not slay them.",
    "answer": ["Daughters"],
    "options": ["Children", "Daughters", "Boys"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2626",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:14",
    "question": "The Lamanites had compassion for the daughters of the Nephites and they were charmed with the beauty of their women.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2627",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos19:15",
    "question": "The Lamanites did spare the lives of the Nephites and took them captives and carried them back to the land of_____.",
    "answer": ["Nephi"],
    "options": ["Nephi", "Shemlon", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2628",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:15",
    "question": "The Lamanites wanted the Nephites to deliver up their property and King Noah and even one half of all they possessed and to pay tribute to the king of the Lamanites from year to year.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2629",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:17",
    "question": "Among those that were taken captive by the Lamanites was one of the sons of King Noah; and he desired that his father should not be destroyed.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2630",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos19:17",
    "question": "What was the name of King Noah son who was a just man and was not ignorant of the iniquities of his father?",
    "answer": ["Limhi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2631",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos19:18",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Gideon sent men into the wilderness secretly, to search for King_____ and those that were with him.",
    "answer": ["Noah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2632",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos19:20",
    "question": "The people were angry with King Noah and caused that he should suffer, even unto death by_____.",
    "answer": ["Fire"],
    "options": ["Hanging", "Fire", "Firing Squad"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2633",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos19:23",
    "question": "The people told the men of_____ that they had slain the king, and his priests had fled from them farther into the wilderness.",
    "answer": ["Gideon"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2634",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos19:26",
    "question": "Limhi was the son of King Noah that had the kingdom conferred upon him by the people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2635",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos19:27",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King_____ began to establish the kingdom and to establish peace among his people.",
    "answer": ["Limhi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2636",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos20:1",
    "question": "What was the name of the place where the daughters of the Lamanites gathered themselves together to sing, and to dance and to make themselves merry?",
    "answer": ["Shemlon"],
    "options": ["Shemlon", "Waters Of Mormon", "Shilom"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2637",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos20:5",
    "question": "How many daughters of the Lamanites did the priests of King Noah carry into the wilderness?",
    "answer": ["24"],
    "options": ["24", "34", "44"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2638",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos20:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the_____ were angry with the people of Limhi because they thought it was them that had carried away their daughters into the wilderness.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2639",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:8",
    "question": "The king of the Lamanites himself and his armies went to the land of Nephi to destroy the people of Limhi because of what they thought they had done.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2640",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos20:8",
    "question": "King Limhi discovered the Lamanites from the _____, even all the preparations of war did he discover; therefore he gathered his people together for war.",
    "answer": ["Tower"],
    "options": ["Tall Balcony", "Highest Wall", "Tower"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2641",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos20:10",
    "question": "The people of King Limhi began to slay the Lamanites and the battle became exceedingly sore, and they fought like_____ for their prey.",
    "answer": ["Lions"],
    "options": ["Lions", "Tigers", "Leopards"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2642",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos20:11",
    "question": "The people of King Limhi began to drive the Lamanites before them; they fought for their lives, and for their wives, and for their_____.",
    "answer": ["Children"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2643",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:11",
    "question": "Because to the things that the people of King Limhi were fighting for, they exerted themselves, and like tigers did they fought.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2644",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of King Limhi found the king of the Lamanites among the number of their dead; yet he was not dead.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2645",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:12",
    "question": "Because the flight of the people of the Lamanites was so speedy they thought that their king had died in battle, but actually he was only wounded.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2646",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos20:14,15",
    "question": "The king of the Lamanites had broken the oath that he had previously made with King_____ because he thought that the Nephites had carried away their daughters.",
    "answer": ["Limhi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2647",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:16",
    "question": "King Limhi caused that a search among his people be made so that they could find out which persons were involved in carrying away the daughters of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2648",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos20:17",
    "question": "What is the name of the person who was the captain of the army of King Limhi?",
    "answer": ["Gideon"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2649",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos20:18",
    "question": "Gideon told King Limhi that his father’s priests were the ones who had taken and stolen the daughters of the_____ and that he must tell the Lamanites this to pacify them.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2650",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos20:21",
    "question": "Gideon said that the words of_____ were fulfilled; which he prophesied against them because they would not hearken unto the words of the Lord, and turn from their iniquities.",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2651",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:22",
    "question": "Gideon told King Limhi that is better for them to lose their lives than to be in bondage unto the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2652",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:23",
    "question": "King Limhi told the king of the Lamanites all the things concerning his father, and the priests that had fled into the wilderness and attributed the carrying away of their daughters to them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2653",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:24",
    "question": "After King Limhi told the king of the Lamanites concerning the things about his father and his priests, he was pacified",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2654",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos20:25",
    "question": "The king of the Lamanites did not bow down before the armies of the Lamanites and pleaded on behalf of the people of King Limhi.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2655",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos20:26",
    "question": "The _____saw that the people of King Limhi were without weapons of war and had compassion on them and returned with their king in peace to their own land.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2656",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Limhi and his people returned to the city of_____ and dwelt in the land in peace.",
    "answer": ["Nephi"],
    "options": ["Nephi", "Mormon", "Shemlon"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2657",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:2,3",
    "question": "After many days the Lamanites were stirred up in anger against the Nephites and they did not slay them because of the oath their king had made unto King Limhi.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2658",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:3",
    "question": "The Lamanites began to smite the Nephites on their_____, and exercise authority over them; and began to put heavy burdens upon their backs.",
    "answer": ["Cheeks"],
    "options": ["Backs", "Cheeks", "Behinds"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2659",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:3",
    "question": "The Lamanites began to smite the Nephites on their cheeks and do other things to them and also began to drive them as they would a dumb ass.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2660",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:4",
    "question": "All kind of bad things happened to the Lamanites so that the words of the Lord might be fulfilled.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2661",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:6",
    "question": "The people began to murmur with the king because of their_____; and they began to be desirous to go to battle against the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["Afflictions"],
    "options": ["Downfall", "Sorrow", "Afflictions"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2662",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:7,8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites and Nephites went to battle and the Lamanites did slay many of the_____ and drove them back to their lands.",
    "answer": ["Nephites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2664",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:13",
    "question": "The Nephites did humble themselves even to the dust, subjecting themselves to the yoke of bondage, to be smitten and to be driven to and fro.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2665",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:14",
    "question": "The Nephites did humble themselves even to the depths of humility unto God; and did cry mightily to_____ that he might deliver them out of their afflictions.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["God", "Nephi", "Moses"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2666",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:15",
    "question": "The Lord was slow to hear the cries of the Nephites because of their _____.",
    "answer": ["Iniquities"],
    "options": ["Pride", "Iniquities", "Stubbornness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2667",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:15",
    "question": "The Lord did hear the cries of the Nephities and began to soften the hearts of the_____.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2668",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:15",
    "question": "Even though the Lord heard the cries of the Nephities he still did not deliver them out of bondage.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2669",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:17",
    "question": "During this time in Nephite history there were more men than women.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2670",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:18",
    "question": "King Limhi and his people kept together in a body as much as it was possible, and secured their grain and their_____.",
    "answer": ["Flocks"],
    "options": ["Lands", "Flocks", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2671",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:22",
    "question": "And it came to pass that there was no more disturbance between the Lamanites and the people of King _____; even until the time Ammon and his brethren came into the Land.",
    "answer": ["Limhi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2672",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:23",
    "question": "King Limhi and his Guards discovered_____ and his brethren and supposed they were the priests of Noah.",
    "answer": ["Ammon"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2673",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:23",
    "question": "King Limhi and his guards did not discover Ammon and his brethren and did not supposed that they were the priests of King Noah.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2674",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:23",
    "question": "King Limhi caused that Ammon and his brethren should be taken, and bound, and cast into prison.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2675",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:24",
    "question": "King Limhi found that Ammon and his brethren were his brethren, and had come from the land of_____.",
    "answer": ["Zarahemla"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2676",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:24",
    "question": "King Limhi was not filled with joy when he found out that Ammon and his brethren had come from the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2677",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:25",
    "question": "Before the coming of Ammon, King Limhi had sent a small number of men to search for the land of_____; but they could not find it and got lost in the wilderness.",
    "answer": ["Zarahemla"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2678",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:26",
    "question": "The search party that King Limhi sent out discovered a land which had been peopled and covered with dry bones.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2679",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:26",
    "question": "King Limhi’s search party thought the land they had discovered was the land of Zarahemla and returned to the land of_____.",
    "answer": ["Nephi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2680",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:27",
    "question": "King Limhi’s search party brought a record with them, even a record of the people whose_____ they had found.",
    "answer": ["Bones"],
    "options": ["Bones", "Bodies", "Weapons"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2681",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:27",
    "question": "The record that King Lemhi’s search party found was engraven on plates made of _____.",
    "answer": ["Ore"],
    "options": ["Brass", "Gold", "Ore"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2682",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:28",
    "question": "King Limhi was filled with joy because he found out from Ammon that King_____ had a gift from God, whereby he could interpret such engravings.",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2683",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:29,30",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren were filled with sorrow because so many of their brethren had been slain and did mourn the death of_____.",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2684",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:30",
    "question": "Alma1 and the people that fled with him formed a church of_____ though the strength and power of God.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2685",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:31",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren did mourn for Alma1 and the people that fled with him because they did not know where they had gone.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2686",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:31",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren had entered a covenant with God to serve him and keep his_____.",
    "answer": ["Commandments"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2687",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:32",
    "question": "Since the coming of Ammon, King Limhi had also entered into a covenant with God and also so many of his people, to serve him and keep his commandments.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2688",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:33",
    "question": "King Limhi and his people were desirous to be baptized; but there was no one in the land that had the_____ from God.",
    "answer": ["Authority"],
    "options": ["Say So", "Authority", "Gift"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2689",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos21:33",
    "question": "Ammon decl1ned to baptized King Limhi and his people because he considered himself an unworthy servant.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2690",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos21:35",
    "question": "King Limhi and his people were desirous to be baptized as a witness and a_____ that they were willing to serve God with all their hearts.",
    "answer": ["Testimony"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2691",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos22:2",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Ammon and King Limhi and his people could not find a way to deliver themselves out of bondage from the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2692",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos22:3,4",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Gideon went forth and stood before King Limhi and desired to speak to him and his people that he might be his servant and deliver them form bondage.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2693",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos22:7",
    "question": "Gideon’s plan was to pay tribute to the Lamanites with_____, and get them drunk and he would pass though the secret pass while they were drunk with sleep.",
    "answer": ["W1ne"],
    "options": ["Gold", "W1ne", "Silver"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2694",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos22:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Limhi would not hearken to the words of Gideon.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2695",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos22:10",
    "question": "King Limhi caused that his people should gather their flocks together; and he sent the tribute of w1ne to the_____.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2696",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos22:11",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of King Limhi did depart by night into the wilderness towards the land of_____, being led by Ammon and his brethren.",
    "answer": ["Zarahemla"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2697",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos22:13",
    "question": "After many days in the wilderness they arrived in the land of Zarahemla, and jo1ned the people of King _____, and became his subjects.",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2698",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos22:14",
    "question": "King Mosiah received King Lemhi and his people with joy; and also received their records, and also the records which had been found by King Lemhi’s search party.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2699",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos22:15,16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites sent an army to pursue King Limhi and his people; and after two days they could no longer follow their tracks and were lost in the_____.",
    "answer": ["Wilderness"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2700",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:1",
    "question": "Who warned Alma1 and his people that the armies of King Noah would come upon them?",
    "answer": ["The Lord"],
    "options": ["The Lord", "Gideon", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2701",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:1",
    "question": "Alma1 and his people gathered together their flocks, and took their grain, and departed into the wilderness before the armies of King Noah.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2702",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:2",
    "question": "Who strengthen Alma1 and his people that the people of King Noah could not overtake them?",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2703",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:4",
    "question": "After traveling for eight days in the wilderness, Alma1 and his people came to a land that was beautiful and pleasant, a land of pure_____.",
    "answer": ["Water"],
    "options": ["Gold", "Pleasantries", "Water"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2704",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:5",
    "question": "Alma1 and his people pitched their tents, and began to till the ground, and began to build_____; they were industrious, and did labor exceedingly.",
    "answer": ["Buildings"],
    "options": ["Houses", "Barns", "Buildings"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2705",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:6",
    "question": "The people were desirous that_____ should be their king, because he was beloved by all his people.",
    "answer": ["Alma"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2706",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:7",
    "question": "Alma1 told the people that it was not expedient that they should have a king.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2707",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:7",
    "question": "The Lord has said:”Ye shall not esteem one flesh above another, or one_____ shall not think himself above another”.",
    "answer": ["Man"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2708",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:8",
    "question": "Alma1 told the people: That if it was possible that they could always have just men to be there kings it would be well for them to have a king.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2709",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:9",
    "question": "Alma1 reminded the people of the iniquity King Noah and his priests had caused the people to commit and that he himself was caught in a snare.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2710",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:10",
    "question": "The Lord heard the cries of Alma1 and did answer his prayers and he made him an_____ in his hands in bringing so many people to the knowledge of the truth.",
    "answer": ["Instrument"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2711",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:11",
    "question": "Alma1 gloried in being an instrument in the hands of the Lord because he said he was a worthy servant.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2712",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:12",
    "question": "Alma1 reminded the people how they had been oppressed by King Noah and his priests, and had been in bondage and that they had been brought to iniquity by them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2713",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:12",
    "question": "Alma1 also told the people that they were bound by the bands of_____.",
    "answer": ["Iniquity"],
    "options": ["Death", "Sin", "Iniquity"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2714",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:13",
    "question": "Alma1 told the people that they had been delivered by the power of_____ out of these bonds; even out of the hands of King Noah and his people, and also from the bonds of iniquity.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2715",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:13",
    "question": "Alma1 told the people to stand fast in this liberty wherewith they had been made free, and that they must trust no_____ to be a king over them.",
    "answer": ["Man"],
    "options": ["Woman", "Lamanite", "Man"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2716",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:14",
    "question": "Alma1 told the people to trust no one to be there teacher or minister, except he be a man of_____, walking in his ways and keeping his commandments.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2717",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:16",
    "question": "Alma1 was the people’s_____ priest, he being the founder of their church.",
    "answer": ["High"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2718",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:17",
    "question": "And it came to pass that none received authority to preach or teach except it were given to him from God; and Alma consecrated all their priests and teachers and they were just men.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2719",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:19",
    "question": "The people began to prosper exceedingly in the land; and they called the land Helam, and also build a city and called it_____.",
    "answer": ["Helam"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2720",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:21",
    "question": "Nevertheless the Lord sees fit to chasten his people; yea, and he also tries their patience and their_____.",
    "answer": ["Faith"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2721",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:22",
    "question": "Nevertheless; whosoever puts his trust in the Lord the same shall be_____ up at the last day.",
    "answer": ["Lifted"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2722",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:23",
    "question": "Mormon wrote that he would show unto us that the people were brought into bondage, and none could deliver them but the Lord their God, even the God of Abraham and Isaac and of_____.",
    "answer": ["Jacob"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2723",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:24",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lord did deliver the people, and he did show forth his mighty_____.",
    "answer": ["Power"],
    "options": ["Rod", "Arm", "Power"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2724",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:25",
    "question": "The people did rejoice because of their deliverance; and while they were tilling the land of Helam, behold an army of the_____ came upon them.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2725",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:27",
    "question": "Alma1 went forth and stood among the people and exhorted them that they should not be frightened; but that they should remember the_____ their God and he would deliver them.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2726",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:28",
    "question": "The people began to cry unto the Lord that he would soften the hearts of the Lamanites, that they would spare them, and their wives and children.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2727",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:28",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lord did not hear the cries of the people because of their iniquities, and he did not soften the hearts of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2728",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:30",
    "question": "The armies of the Lamanites which had followed after the people of King Limhi were lost in the wilderness for_____ days.",
    "answer": ["Many"],
    "options": ["3", "4", "Many"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2729",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:31",
    "question": "The armies of the Lamanites found those priests of King Noah in a place they called Amulon.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2730",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:32",
    "question": "What was the name of the priest that was the leader of the priests of King Noah?",
    "answer": ["Amulon"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2731",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:33",
    "question": "Amulon sent forth their wives, (who were the daughters of the_____), to plead with their brethren, that they should not destroy their husbands.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2732",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:34",
    "question": "The Lamanites had compassion on Amulon and his brethren, and did not destroy them because of their_____.",
    "answer": ["Wives"],
    "options": ["Gold", "Silver", "Wives"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2733",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:35",
    "question": "Amulon and his brethren did join the Lamanites, and they were traveling in the wilderness in search of the land of Nephi, when they discovered the land of Helam.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2734",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:36",
    "question": "The Lamanites promised unto_____ and his brethren, that if they would show them the way which led to the land of Nephi that they would grant unto them their lives and liberty.",
    "answer": ["Alma"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2735",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos23:37",
    "question": "After Alma1 had shown the Lamanites the way that led to the land of Nephi they did not keep their_____.",
    "answer": ["Promise"],
    "options": ["Vows", "Promise", "Word"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2736",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos23:38",
    "question": "The remainder of them went to the land of Nephi; and a part of them returned to the land of Helam.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2737",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos23:39",
    "question": "The king of the Lamanites granted unto_____ that he should be a king and a ruler over his people, who were in the land of Helam.",
    "answer": ["Amulon"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2738",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amulon did not gain favor with the king of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2739",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:2",
    "question": "Because the Lamanites had taken possession of all the lands; the king of the Lamanites had appointed kings over all the lands.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2740",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:3",
    "question": "What was the name of the king of the Lamanites who was called after the name of his father and was a king over a numerous people?",
    "answer": ["Laman"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2741",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos24:4",
    "question": "King Laman appointed_____ of the brethren of Amulon in every land; and thus the language of Nephi began to be taught among all the people of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["Teachers"],
    "options": ["Teachers", "Priests", "Professors"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2742",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:5",
    "question": "The Lamanites were a people who were friendly one with another; nevertheless they did know God.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2743",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:5",
    "question": "The brethren of Amulon did not teach the Lamanites anything concerning the Lord their God, neither the Law of_____.",
    "answer": ["Moses"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2744",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:5",
    "question": "The brethren of Amulon also did not teach the Lamanites anything concerning the words of_____.",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2745",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:6",
    "question": "The brethren of Amulon taught the Lamanites that they should keep their record, and that they might write one to another.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2746",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:7",
    "question": "The Lamanites began to increase in riches, and began to trade with one another and wax great, and began to be a cunning and a_____ people, as to the wisdom of the world.",
    "answer": ["Wise"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2747",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:7",
    "question": "The Lamanites were a very cunning people, delighting in all manner of_____ and plunder, except it was among their own brethren.",
    "answer": ["Wickedness"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2748",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amulon began to exercise authority over_____ and his brethren.",
    "answer": ["Alma"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2749",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:9",
    "question": "Amulon knew that Alma1 had been one of King Noah’s priests, and that it was he that believed the words of_____.",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2750",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:9",
    "question": "Amulon began to exercise authority over Alma1 and the Nephites and put tasks upon them, and put task-masters over them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2751",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:10",
    "question": "And it came to pass that so great were the afflictions of the Nephites that they began to cry mightily to God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2752",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:11",
    "question": "Who commanded the Nephites to stop their cries to the Lord; that whosoever should be found calling upon God should be put to death?",
    "answer": ["Amulon"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2753",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos24:12",
    "question": "Alma1 and his people did not raise their voices to the Lord their God, but did pour out their_____ to him: and he did know the thoughts of their hearts.",
    "answer": ["Hearts"],
    "options": ["Souls", "Hearts", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2754",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos24:13",
    "question": "The voice of the Lord came to the people in their afflictions, saying:  Lift up your_____ and be of good comfort, for I know of the covenant which ye have made unto me.",
    "answer": ["Heads"],
    "options": ["Heads", "Arms", "Swords"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2755",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:14",
    "question": "The Lord did not ease the burdens of the Nephites which were put upon their shoulders.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2756",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:14",
    "question": "The Lord eased the burdens of the Nephites because he wanted them to know and stand as a witness that he does visit his people in their_____.",
    "answer": ["Afflictions"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2757",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:15",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the burdens which were laid upon Alma1 and his brethren were made light; and they did submit cheerfully and with patience to all the will of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2758",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:16",
    "question": "So great was their faith and the patience of the people of Alma1 that the voice of the Lord came unto them and said tomorrow he would deliver them from_____.",
    "answer": ["Bondage"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2759",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:19",
    "question": "The Lord caused that a deep_____ to come upon the Lamanites and all their tasks-masters were in a profound sleep.",
    "answer": ["Sleep"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2760",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:20",
    "question": "Alma1 and his people departed into the wilderness and after they had traveled all day they pitched their tents in a valley, and they called the valley_____, because he had led their way.",
    "answer": ["Alma"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2761",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos24:21,22",
    "question": "Alma1 and all those that could speak lifted their voices in the praises of their God, and gave him thanks for delivering them from bondage in the valley of Alma1.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2762",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:23",
    "question": "Who told Alma1 to leave the valley and the land they were in because the Lamanites were in pursuit of them?",
    "answer": ["Lord", "God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2763",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos24:25",
    "question": "After Alma1 and his people left the valley of Alma they traveled for twelve days and arrived in the land of_____; and King Mosiah did also receive them with joy.",
    "answer": ["Zarahemla"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2764",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:2",
    "question": "Zarahemla was a descendant of_____.",
    "answer": ["Mulek"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2765",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:2",
    "question": "The word Mulekites never appears in the Book of Mormon text.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2766",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25",
    "question": "The word “Mulekites” only appears in the heading of Chapter#25 and never again in the entire Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2767",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25",
    "question": "Someone made up the name of “Mulekites” in the Book of Mormon and put it on the heading of Chapter #25.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2768",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:2",
    "question": "There are no such people as Mulekites ever mentioned in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1773",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:2",
    "question": "Who was Zarahemla?",
    "answer": ["Mulek"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2769",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:2",
    "question": "The so called “Mulekites' Were the people Zarahemla who were descendants of Mulek",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2770",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:3",
    "question": "There were more Lamanites than the people of Nephi and of the people of Zarahemla put together.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2771",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King Mosiah did read, and caused to be read, the records of King_____ to his people.",
    "answer": ["Zeniff"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2772",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:5",
    "question": "King Mosiah read the record of King Zeniff from the time they left the land of Zarahemla until they returned again.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2773",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:6",
    "question": "King Mosiah also read the account of_____ and his brethren, and all their afflictions, from the time they left the land of Zarahemla until the time they returned again.",
    "answer": ["Alma"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2774",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:7",
    "question": "When King Mosiah had made an end of reading the records, his people who tarried in the land and struck with wonder and amazement.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2775",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:9",
    "question": "The people of King Mosiah were filled with sorrow, and even shed many_____ of sorrow because so many of their brethren had been slain by the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["Tears"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2776",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:11",
    "question": "The people of King Mosiah were filled with pain and anguish for the welfare of the souls of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2777",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the children of Amulon and his brethren, who had taken to wife the daughters of the Lamanites; were not displeased with the conduct of their fathers.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2778",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:12",
    "question": "The children of Amulon and his brethren were so displeased with the conduct of their fathers, that they would no longer be called by the names of their fathers.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2779",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:12",
    "question": "The children of Amulon and his brethren took it upon themselves the name of Nephi, that they might be called the children of Nephi and be numbered among those who were_____.",
    "answer": ["Nephites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2780",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:13",
    "question": "All the people of Zarahemla were numbered with the Nephites; and this because the kingdom had been conferred upon none but those who were descendant’s of_____.",
    "answer": ["Nephi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2781",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:14",
    "question": "When King Mosiah had made an end of his speaking and reading to the people, he desired that_____ should also speak to the people.",
    "answer": ["Alma"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2782",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:15",
    "question": "Alma1 did speak unto the people, going from one body to another, preaching unto the people repentance and_____ on the Lord.",
    "answer": ["Faith"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2783",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:16",
    "question": "Alma1 did exhort the people of King Limhi and his brethren, and all those that had been delivered out of bondage; that they should remember that it was the_____ that had delivered them.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2784",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:17",
    "question": "After Alma1 had taught the people many things and made an end to his speaking, King Limhi and all his people were desirous to be baptized.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2785",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:18",
    "question": "Alma1 did go forth into the water and baptize the people in the manner that he had baptized his brethren in the Waters of_____.",
    "answer": ["Mormon"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2786",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:19",
    "question": "And it came to pass that King_____ granted unto Alma1 that he might establish churches throughout the land of Zarahemla, and gave him power to ordain priests and teacher over every church.",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2787",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:20",
    "question": "One of the reasons King Mosiah granted Alma1 to ordain priest and teachers throughout the land was because there were so many people that they could not all be taught by one or more persons",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2788",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:21",
    "question": "Every different priest and teacher taught what they desired in their heart.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2789",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:22",
    "question": "Even though there were many churches throughout the land of Zarahemla, they were all one church of_____.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2790",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos25:23",
    "question": "And it came to pass that whosoever was desirous to take upon them the name of_____, or of God, they did join the churches of God.",
    "answer": ["Christ"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2791",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos25:24",
    "question": "The Lord did not pour out his Spirit upon those that were baptized; therefore they were not blessed and did not prosper in the land.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2792",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that there were many of the rising generation that could not understand the words of King_____, because they had been little children when he had spoken to the people.",
    "answer": ["Benjamin"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2793",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:2",
    "question": "Many of the rising generation did not believe concerning the_____ of the dead, neither did they believe concerning the coming of Christ.",
    "answer": ["Resurrection"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2794",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:3",
    "question": "Because many of the rising generation did not believe what King Benjamin had taught, they could not understand the word of God; and their hearts were hardened.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2795",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:4",
    "question": "Many of the rising generation would not be baptized; neither would they join the church of God and they were a separate people as to their faith, and rema1ned so ever after.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2796",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos26:4",
    "question": "Many of the rising generation rema1ned in their carnal and _____state; for they would not call upon the Lord their God.",
    "answer": ["Sinful"],
    "options": ["Bad", "Lustful", "Sinful"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2797",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:5",
    "question": "In the reign of King_____ there were more people that did not believe in God; and because of dissensions among the brethren they became more numerous.",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2798",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that those that did not belong to the church; did deceive many with their _____words, who were in the church.",
    "answer": ["Flattering"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2799",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:6",
    "question": "It became expedient that those that those who committed sin, that were in the church, should be admonished by the church.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2800",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma1 did not know what to do because there were many witnesses against the sinners, and people stood and testified of their iniquity in abundance.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2801",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:10",
    "question": "There had not any such thing happened before in the church; therefore_____ was troubled in spirit and he caused that they be brought before King Mosiah.",
    "answer": ["Alma"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2802",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:12",
    "question": "King Mosiah said unto Alma1:  “Behold, I judge them not; therefore I deliver them into thy hands to be judged”.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2803",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:13",
    "question": "Because Alma1 was troubled in spirit; he went and inquired of the_____ what he should do concerning those that had sinned because he did not want to do judge wrong.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2804",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:14",
    "question": "The Lord blessed Alma1 because of his exceeding faith in the words that had been said by his servant_____.",
    "answer": ["Abinidi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2805",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:17,18",
    "question": "The Lord also blessed Alma1 because he had established a church; and because some of the people were willing to bear his name.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2806",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos26:19",
    "question": "The Lord blessed Alma1 because he had inquired of him concerning what to do with the_____.",
    "answer": ["Transgressors"],
    "options": [
      "Transgressors",
      "Righteous",
      "The People That Were Not Of The Church"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2807",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:20",
    "question": "The Lord made a covenant with Alma1 that he would have_____ life if he would serve him and go forth in his name, and shall gather together his sheep.",
    "answer": ["Eternal"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2808",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos26:21",
    "question": "The Lord told Alma1 that those who will hear his_____ shall be his sheep; and he will receive them into the church and also receive them.",
    "answer": ["Voice"],
    "options": ["Shouts", "Voice", "Trumpet"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2809",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:22",
    "question": "The Lord told Alma1 that it was Alma1’s church and that he would forgive them freely if they took upon themselves his name.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2810",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:23",
    "question": "For it is I that have created them; and it is I that grants unto him that believe in me until the end, a place at my_____ hand.",
    "answer": ["Right"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2811",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos26:25",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that when the_____ trumpet shall sound then shall they that never knew me come forth and shall stand before me.",
    "answer": ["Second"],
    "options": ["First", "Second", "Third"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2812",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:26",
    "question": "When the second trumpet shall make its sound those that did not believe in the Lord their God shall know that he is their Redeemer; but they would not be redeemed.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2813",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:27",
    "question": "After the second trumpet shall sound, the Lord will confess to those that came forward and did not believe in the Lord as their Redeemer that he never knew them; and they shall depart into an everlasting fire.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2814",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:27",
    "question": "The Lord has prepared an everlasting fire for the devil and his_____.",
    "answer": ["Angels"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2815",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:28",
    "question": "The Lord told Alma1 that he that will not hear his voice, the same shall he not receive into his church, and that he would not receive them at the last day.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2816",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:29",
    "question": "The Lord told Alma1: He that confesses his sins before him and the Lord, and repents in the sincerity of his_____, his shall you forgive, and I will forgive him also.",
    "answer": ["Heart"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2817",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:31",
    "question": "You shall also forgive one another your trespasses; for verily I say unto you, he that doesn’t forgive his neighbor’s trespasses when he says that he repents, the same has brought himself under_____.",
    "answer": ["Condemnation"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2818",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:32",
    "question": "Those of us that will not repent of our sins, the same shall not be numbered among the Lord’s people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2819",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:33",
    "question": "Alma1 wrote the words he had heard from the Lord that he might have them to judge the people of the church according to the commandments of_____.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2820",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos26:36",
    "question": "Those that did not confess their sins and repent of their iniquity, the same were not numbered among the people of the church, and their names were_____ out from the records.",
    "answer": ["Blotted"],
    "options": ["Erased", "Inked", "Blotted"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2821",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:37",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____ did regulate the affairs of the church; and they began again to have peace and to prosper exceedingly in the affairs of the church.",
    "answer": ["Alma"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2822",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos26:38",
    "question": "Alma1 and his fellow laborers did walk in all diligence, teaching the word of God in all things, suffering all matter of afflictions, being persecuted by all those that were not of the church.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2823",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos26:39",
    "question": "Alma1 and his fellow laborers did admonish there brethren; and they were also admonished, every one by the word or_____.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2824",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos26:39",
    "question": "The Lord commanded those that had committed sins to_____ without ceasing, and to give thanks in all things.",
    "answer": ["Pray"],
    "options": ["Work", "Labor", "Pray"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2825",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:1",
    "question": "The persecutions which were inflicted on the church by the unbelievers became so great that the church began to murmur.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2826",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:1",
    "question": "The people of the church compla1ned to Alma1 and to King_____, and King Mosiah consulted with his priests.",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2827",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos27:2",
    "question": "What did King Mosiah send out throughout all the land that there should not be any persecutions to those that did belong to the church of God?",
    "answer": ["Proclamation"],
    "options": ["Text Message", "Proclamation", "Letter"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2828",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:4",
    "question": "It was not a commandment that there should be no pride or any haught1ness to disturb the peace of the people; that every man should esteem his neighbor as himself.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2829",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:5",
    "question": "Everyone was to labor with their own hands for their support; even all the priests and teachers, and doing these things, they did have the grace of God in abundance.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2831",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:8",
    "question": "The sons of King Mosiah were numbered among the unbelievers.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2832",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:8",
    "question": "One of the sons of Alma1 was also numbered among the unbelievers and his name was _____, he being called after his father.",
    "answer": ["Alma"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2833",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:8",
    "question": "Alma the Younger was a very wicked and idolatrous man; and he was a man of many words and began to speak flattering words to the people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2834",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos27:8",
    "question": "Because of the words of Alma the Younger he led many of the people to do after the manner of his_____.",
    "answer": ["Iniquities"],
    "options": ["Pleasures", "Ways", "Iniquities"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2835",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:9",
    "question": "Alma the Younger became a great hindrance to the prosperity of the church of God; stealing away the_____ of the people and causing much dissension among them.",
    "answer": ["Hearts"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2836",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:9",
    "question": "Because of the words that Alma the Younger flattered the people with, he gave a chance to the enemy of_____ to exercise his power over them.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2837",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:10",
    "question": "Alma the Younger and the sons of King Mosiah went about secretly seeking to destroy the church of God, and to lead astray the people of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2838",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:11",
    "question": "Who appeared to Alma the Younger and to the sons of King Mosiah as they went about rebelling against God?  An angel of the",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2839",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:11",
    "question": "The angel of the Lord spoke as it were a voice of thunder, which caused the earth to shake upon which Alma the Younger and the sons of King Mosiah stood.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2840",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:12",
    "question": "So great was the astonishment to Alma the Younger and the sons of King Mosiah that they fell to the earth, and could not understand the words which the_____ spoke to them.",
    "answer": ["Angel"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2841",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:13",
    "question": "The Angel asked Alma the Younger why he persecuted the church of God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2842",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:14",
    "question": "Alma the Elder had prayed with much_____ concerning his son that he may come to the knowledge of the truth.",
    "answer": ["Faith"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2843",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:14",
    "question": "The Angel of the Lord came to convince Alma the Younger of the power and authority of God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2844",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos27:14",
    "question": "The Angel of the Lord also came to convince Alma the Younger that the prayers of his_____ might be answered according to their faith in him.",
    "answer": ["Servants"],
    "options": ["Subjects", "Servants", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2845",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:15",
    "question": "Who sent the Angel to say the things he said to Alma the Younger?",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2846",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:16",
    "question": "The Angel of the Lord told Alma the Younger to go his way and to not seek to destroy the church of God no more.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2847",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:18",
    "question": "Alma the Younger and the sons of King Mosiah fell a second time to the earth; they knew that there was nothing except the power of God that could shake the earth and cause it to_____.",
    "answer": ["Tremble"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2848",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:19",
    "question": "The astonishment of Alma the Younger was so great that he became dumb, that he could not open his_____; and he became weak and could not move his hands.",
    "answer": ["Mouth"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2849",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos27:19",
    "question": "Who was taken and laid before his father?",
    "answer": ["Alma The Younger"],
    "options": ["Sons Of King Mosiah", "Alma The Younger", "Helaman"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2850",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:20",
    "question": "When the sons of King Mosiah rehearsed to Alma the Elder what had happened to them, he wasn’t happy.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2851",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:20",
    "question": "Alma the Elder knew that it was the power to God that could only have stuck Alma the Younger dumb, therefore, he rejoiced.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2852",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:21",
    "question": "Alma the Elder caused that the people gather together so they might witness what the_____ had done to his son.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2853",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:22",
    "question": "Who caused that the priests should assemble themselves together to pray and to fast for Alma the Younger?",
    "answer": ["Elder"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2854",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:22",
    "question": "The_____ prayed to the Lord their God that he would open the mouth of Alma the Younger, that he might speak, and also that his limbs might receive their strength.",
    "answer": ["Priest"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2855",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:22",
    "question": "The priests also prayed to the Lord their God that the _____of the people might be opened to see and know of the goodness and glory of God.",
    "answer": ["Eyes"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2856",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos27:23",
    "question": "How many days and nights did the priests fast and pray to the Lord their God that the limbs of Alma the Younger might received their strength.",
    "answer": ["Two Days And Two Nights"],
    "options": [
      "One Day And One Night",
      "Two Days And Two Nights",
      "Three Days And Three Nights"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "2857",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:23",
    "question": "When Alma the Younger rega1ned his strength he began to speak to the priests and bid them to be of good comfort.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2858",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:24",
    "question": "Alma the Younger also told the priests that he had repented of his sins, and had been redeemed by the Lord and that he was born of the Spirit.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2859",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:25",
    "question": "The Lord told Alma the Younger that all_____ and all nations, kindreds, tongues and people must be born again; yea born of God.",
    "answer": ["Mankind"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2860",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:25",
    "question": "We must all be born again of God, changed from our carnal and fallen state, to a state of_____, being redeemed of God, becoming his sons and daughters.",
    "answer": ["Righteousness"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2861",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:26",
    "question": "Unless we are changed and become new people we can not inherit the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2862",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:29",
    "question": "Alma the Younger said that his soul had been redeemed from the gall of_____ and bonds of iniquity.",
    "answer": ["Bitterness"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2863",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos27:29",
    "question": "Alma the Younger said that he was in the darkest_____; but that he now beheld the marvelous light of God.",
    "answer": ["Abyss"],
    "options": ["Black Hole", "Abyss", "Alley"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2864",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:30",
    "question": "Alma the Younger said that he had rejected his Redeemer but that now he knew that he would come and that he remembers every creature that he has created.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2865",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:30",
    "question": "According to Alma the Younger; only the righteous shall the Lord manifest himself to them.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2866",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:31",
    "question": "Every_____ shall bow, and every tongue shall confess before him that he is God.",
    "answer": ["Knee"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2867",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:31",
    "question": "Those that lived in the world without God in their lives; shall confess that the judgment of an everlasting punishment is just upon them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2868",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:31",
    "question": "Those that receive the judgment of an everlasting punishment shall quake, and tremble, and shrink beneath the glance of the Lords all-_____ eye.",
    "answer": ["Searching"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2869",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:32",
    "question": "And it came to pass that from this time forward Alma the Younger and the Sons of King Mosiah began to preach the word of God in much tribulation.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2870",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos27:32",
    "question": "Alma the Younger and the Sons of King Mosiah did not suffer much tribulation or persecution from the unbelievers, and were smitten by many of them.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2871",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:33",
    "question": "Alma the Younger and the Sons of King Mosiah confirmed their faith unto the people, and exhorting them with much travail to keep the_____ of God.",
    "answer": ["Commandments"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2872",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:34",
    "question": "King Mosiah had how many sons that were with Alma the Younger preaching the word of God?",
    "answer": ["Four"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2873",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:34",
    "question": "The names of King Mosiah’s sons were:  Ammon, Aaron, Omner, and_____.",
    "answer": ["Himni"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2874",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:35",
    "question": "Alma the Younger and the sons of King Mosiah traveled throughout the land of_____, zealously striving to repair all the injuries they had done to the church of God.",
    "answer": ["Zarahemla"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2875",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:36",
    "question": "Alma the Younger and the Sons of King Mosiah were_____ in the hands of God in bringing many to the knowledge of the truth and to the knowledge of their Redeemer.",
    "answer": ["Instruments"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2876",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos27:37",
    "question": "Alma the Younger and the Sons of King Mosiah did publish peace; they did publish good tidings of good; and they did declare unto the people that the_____ reigns.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2877",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:1",
    "question": "The Sons of King Mosiah desired from King Mosiah permission to preach the things which they had heard, and they might impart the word of God to their brethren, the_____.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2878",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:2",
    "question": "The Sons of King Mosiah did not want to bring the Lamanites to the knowledge of the Lord their God.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2879",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:2",
    "question": "The Sons of King Mosiah wanted to convince the Lamanites of the iniquity of their fathers; and that they might cure them of the hatred towards the_____.",
    "answer": ["Nephites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2880",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:2",
    "question": "The Sons of King Mosiah also wanted to convince the Lamanites to become friendly to one another, and that there should be no more contentions in all the land the Lord had given them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2881",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos28:3",
    "question": "The Sons of King Mosiah were desirous that _____ should be declared to every creature, because they could not bear that any human should perish.",
    "answer": ["Salvation"],
    "options": ["Cleanl1ness", "Neatness", "Salvation"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2882",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos28:3",
    "question": "The very thought that any_____ should endure endless torment did cause the Sons of King Mosiah to quake and tremble.",
    "answer": ["Soul"],
    "options": ["Creature", "Soul", "Person"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2883",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:4",
    "question": "The Spirit of the Lord did work upon the Sons of King Mosiah because they were the vilest of sinners.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2884",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos28:4",
    "question": "The Lord saw fit to spare the Sons of King Mosiah in his infinite_____.",
    "answer": ["Mercy"],
    "options": ["Mercy", "Kindness", "Thoughtfulness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2885",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos28:5",
    "question": "How many days did the Sons of King Mosiah plead with him that they might go to the land of Nephi to preach the word of the Lord their God?",
    "answer": ["Many"],
    "options": ["One", "Two", "Many"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2886",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:6",
    "question": "King Mosiah inquired of the_____ if he should let his sons go up among the Lamanites to preach the word of God.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2887",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:7",
    "question": "The Lord told King Mosiah not to let his sons go to the land of Nephi to preach his word among the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2888",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:7",
    "question": "The Lord told King Mosiah that many of the Lamanites would believe the words of his sons and that they shall have eternal life.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2889",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos28:7",
    "question": "The Lord told King Mosiah that he would_____ his sons out of the hands of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["Deliver"],
    "options": ["Protect", "Look Out After", "Deliver"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2890",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:8,9",
    "question": "Because King Mosiah was worried for the welfare of his sons, he did not let them go up to the land of Nephi to preach the word of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2891",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:10",
    "question": "King Mosiah had no one to confer the kingdom upon because there were not any of his sons who would accept the_____.",
    "answer": ["Kingdom"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2892",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:11",
    "question": "King Mosiah had the records which were engraved on the plates of brass and also the Plates of_____, and all the other things he had kept and preserved according to the commandments of God.",
    "answer": ["Nephi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2893",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos28:11",
    "question": "What kind of metal were the plates made of that the people of King Limhi found?",
    "answer": ["Gold"],
    "options": ["Gold", "Brass", "Copper"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2894",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:11",
    "question": "King Mosiah also had the plates of gold that which had been found by the people of_____, which were delivered to him by the hand of King Limhi.  King",
    "answer": ["Limhi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2895",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:12",
    "question": "The people of King Mosiah had great anxiety because they were desirous beyond measure to know concerning those people that had been destroyed.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2896",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos28:13",
    "question": "King Mosiah translated the gold plates found by the people of King Limhi by the means of_____ stones which were fastened into two rims of a bow.",
    "answer": ["Two"],
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2897",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:15",
    "question": "Who had prepared the two stones which were fastened into two rims for the purpose of translating languages?  The Lord,",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2898",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:15",
    "question": "The two stones and two rims were prepared by the Lord that he should discover to every creature who should possess the land of the iniquities and abominations of his people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2899",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:16",
    "question": "Whosoever used the two stones which were fastened into two rims is called a_____, after the manner of old times.",
    "answer": ["Seer"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2900",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:17",
    "question": "King Mosiah gave his people an account of the people that had been destroyed after he had finished translating the gold plates.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2901",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:17",
    "question": "The gold plates conta1ned the account of the people back to the building of the great_____, at the time the Lord had confounded the language.",
    "answer": ["Tower"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2902",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:17",
    "question": "The gold plates also conta1ned the account way back to the creation of what person of old times?",
    "answer": ["Adam"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2903",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:19",
    "question": "Mormon tells us in the Book of Mosiah; that it is expedient that all people should know the things which are written in the account of the gold plates.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2904",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:20",
    "question": "King Mosiah took the plates of brass, and all the things which he had kept and conferred them to whom?",
    "answer": ["Younger"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2905",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:20",
    "question": "In what Book of Mormon book is Alma the Younger made custodian of the 24 plates and other records?",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2906",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:20",
    "question": "King Mosiah also conferred all the records, and also the interpreters to Alma the Younger and commanded him that he should keep and preserve them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2907",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos28:20",
    "question": "King Mosiahdid not command Alma the Younger to keep a record of the people.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2908",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos28:20",
    "question": "King Mosiah commanded that all the things he had conferred upon Alma the Younger to be handed down from one generation to another, even as they had been handed down from the time that _____ left Jerusalem.",
    "answer": ["Lehi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2909",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:2",
    "question": "Which son of King Mosiah did the people wish to be their king and ruler?",
    "answer": ["Aaron"],
    "options": ["Ammon", "Aaron", "Himni"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2910",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:3",
    "question": "Aaron did not want to take upon him the kingdom; neither were any of the Sons of Mosiah willing to take upon them the kingdom.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2911",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:2,Mos29:7",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that the kingdom rightfully belonged to his son _____; and if another was appointed in his stead he feared that contentions would rise among the people.",
    "answer": ["Aaron"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2912",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:7",
    "question": "King Mosiah also feared that contentions among his people would cause wars and the shedding of much blood and pervert the ways of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2913",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:11",
    "question": "Because none of his sons wanted the kingdom; King Mosiah told the people that he would be their king the rest of his days and that they should appoint_____ to judge this people according to the law.",
    "answer": ["Judges"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2914",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:11",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that they should appoint judges that will judge the people according to his commandments.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2915",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:12",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that it is better that a man be should be judged of_____, rather than of man.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2916",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:12",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that the judgments of God are always _____.",
    "answer": ["Just"],
    "options": ["Ok", "Righteous", "Just"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2917",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:12",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that the judgments of men are not always just, like that of the Lord’s.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2918",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:13",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that if it was possible to have just men to be their kings, who would establish the laws of God, who would do even as his father did whose name was King_____.",
    "answer": ["Benjamin"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2919",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:14",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that he himself had labored with all the power and faculties which he possessed, to teach them the commandments of_____.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2920",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:14",
    "question": "King Mosiah taught the people that there should be no wars, no stealing, no plundering and no_____ and no manner of iniquity.",
    "answer": ["Murdering"],
    "options": ["Drinking", "Bad Mouthing", "Murdering"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2921",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:15",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that whosoever had committed iniquity, he had punished them according the_____ which was given to them by their fathers.",
    "answer": ["Law"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2922",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:16",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that because all_____ are not just; it was not expedient that they should have a king or kings to rule over them.",
    "answer": ["Men"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2923",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:17",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people:”For behold; how much iniquity does one wicked king cause to be committed, and what great destruction!",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2924",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:18",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people to remember the iniquities that King Noah had done; and because of his iniquities they were brought into bondage.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2925",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:19",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that if it was not for the interposition of their all-wise_____, they must have rema1ned in bondage until now.",
    "answer": ["Creator"],
    "options": ["Creator", "Nephi", "King Benjamin"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2926",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:19",
    "question": "The word interposition only appears once in the Book of Mormon; and it appears in the Book of_____.",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2927",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:20",
    "question": "The Lord delivered the people because they did humble themselves before _____.",
    "answer": ["The Lord"],
    "options": ["King Mosiah", "King Benjamin", "The Lord"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2928",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:20",
    "question": "Because the people cried mightily to the Lord, he did deliver them out of_____ from the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["Bondage"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2929",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:20",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that the Lord in all cases does work his power among all the children of men, extending the arm of mercy towards them that put their_____ in him.",
    "answer": ["Trust"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2930",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:21",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that they could not dethrone an iniquitous king save it be through much contention, and the shedding of much_____.",
    "answer": ["Blood"],
    "options": ["Skin", "Blood", "Scalps"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2931",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:22",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that an iniquitous king has_____ in iniquity, and tears up the laws of those who have reigned in righteousness before him.",
    "answer": ["Friends"],
    "options": ["Friends", "Power", "The Right Of Way"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2932",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:23",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that an iniquitous king sends laws among them after the manner of his wickedness.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2933",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:23",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that an unrighteous king perverts the ways of_____.",
    "answer": ["Righteousness"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2934",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:25",
    "question": "Who did King Mosiah say gave the laws to there fathers’ to give to them.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2935",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:26",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that it is common for the lesser part of the people to desire that which is not right.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2936",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:27",
    "question": "King Mosiah said to the people that if the time comes that the_____ of the people do choose iniquity; then is the time that the judgments of God will come upon them.",
    "answer": ["Voice"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2937",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:28",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that if the judges they had appointed did not judge according to the law, they should cause that they may be judged of a_____ judge.",
    "answer": ["Higher"],
    "options": ["Better", "Wiser", "Higher"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2938",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:29",
    "question": "King Mosiah said that if the higher judges do not judge righteous judgments; they should cause that a small number of the lower judges gather together and judge them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2939",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:30",
    "question": "King Mosiah commanded the people to have no king and to do all the things that he had told them because of the fear of the_____.",
    "answer": ["Lord"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2940",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:30",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people that if they commit sins and iniquities they shall be answered upon their own_____.",
    "answer": ["Heads"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2941",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:32",
    "question": "King Mosiah desired that the people be equal in the land; especially among his people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2942",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:32",
    "question": "King Mosiah desired that the land be a land of_____, and every man may enjoy his rights and privileges alike.",
    "answer": ["Liberty"],
    "options": ["Wealth", "Liberty", "Freedom"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2943",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:34",
    "question": "King Mosiah told the people many more things which ought not to be; but that the burden should come upon all the people, that every man might bear his part.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2944",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:35",
    "question": "King Mosiah also unfolded unto the people all the disadvantages they labor under, by having an unrighteous_____ to rule over them.",
    "answer": ["King"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2945",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:38",
    "question": "Because of the things that King Mosiah said concerning unrighteous kings; the people relinquished their desires for a king.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2946",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:38",
    "question": "The people became exceedingly anxious that every man should have an equal chance throughout all the land; and every man expressed a willingness to answer for their own_____.",
    "answer": ["Sins"],
    "options": ["Thoughts", "Sins", "Crimes"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2947",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:39",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people assembled themselves together in bodies throughout all the land, to cast their_____, concerning who should be their judges.",
    "answer": ["Voices"],
    "options": ["Votes", "Ballets", "Voices"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2948",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:40",
    "question": "The people did not wax strong in the love towards King Mosiah; and they did not esteem him more over any other man.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2949",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:40",
    "question": "King Mosiah did not delight in the shedding of blood and had established peace throughout the land.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2950",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:40",
    "question": "The people esteemed King _____ exceedingly beyond measure because he had granted unto his people that they should be delivered from all manner of bondage.",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2951",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:41",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people did appoint judges to rule over them, or to be judged according to the_____.",
    "answer": ["Law"],
    "options": ["Commandments", "Rules", "Law"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2952",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:42",
    "question": "Who did the people appoint to be there first chief judge?",
    "answer": ["Younger"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2953",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:42",
    "question": "Alma the Younger was also a high priest because Alma the Elder had conferred that office upon him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2954",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:42",
    "question": "Who had given Alma the Younger charge concerning all the affairs of the church?",
    "answer": ["Elder"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2955",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:43",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma the Younger did walk in the ways of the Lord, and he did keep his commandments, and did judge righteous judgments.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2956",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:40,47",
    "question": "Who was the last king of the people of Nephi?",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2957",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:44",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the reign of the Judges commenced throughout the land of_____, among all the people who were called Nephites.",
    "answer": ["Zarahemla"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2958",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:45",
    "question": "Alma the Elder lived to be_____ years old before he died, having lived to fulfil the commandments of God.",
    "answer": ["82"],
    "options": ["72", "82", "92"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2959",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:46",
    "question": "How many years did King Mosiah reign for before he passed away?",
    "answer": ["33"],
    "options": ["23", "33", "43"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2960",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos29:46",
    "question": "How old was King Mosiah when he passed away?",
    "answer": ["63"],
    "options": ["63", "73", "83"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2961",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mos29:47",
    "question": "King Mosiah left his son Orihah to reign after him",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2962",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:47",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the reign of the kings over the people of Nephi ended; and so did the days of Alma the_____, who was the founder of their church.",
    "answer": ["Elder"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2963",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos29:46-47­",
    "question": "Who was the last king of the Nephites?",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4220",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos8:14",
    "question": "Gazelem is another name for which one of these prophets of the Lord?",
    "answer": ["Nephi"],
    "options": ["Nephi", "Mosiah", "Lehi"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2010",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:7-8",
    "question": "Who did King Benjamin say shall suffer temptations, and pain of body, thirst, and fatigue, even more than man can suffer?",
    "answer": ["Jesus"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2084",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos5:5, Mos3:26",
    "question": "Who had spoken to King Benjamin and told him to tell the people not to bring upon themselves a never-ending torment; that they may not drink out of the cup of wrath of God?.",
    "answer": ["An Angel"],
    "options": ["An Angel", "Nephi", "Enos"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2111",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos7:4-5",
    "question": "How many days did Ammon and his brethren wonder in the wilderness before they came to a hill; which is north of the land of Shilom, and pitched their tents.",
    "answer": ["40"],
    "options": ["40", "50", "60"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2112",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos7:6",
    "question": "Of the party of sixteen men that went with Ammon, only himself and _____ of his brethren met with the king of the people of the land of Nephi/Shilom.",
    "answer": ["3"],
    "options": ["2", "3", "4"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2170",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos8:11-12",
    "question": "King Limhi asked_____ if he was able to translate the twenty-four plates that his people had brought back and in if he knew of anyone that could.",
    "answer": ["Ammon"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2304",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos11:12-13",
    "question": "The land that King Noah possessed and caused that a very high tower be built was called_____.",
    "answer": ["Shilom"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2307",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos11:13 & Omni1-12,13",
    "question": "What was the name of the land that had been a resort for the Nephites when they were told by the Lord to flee into the wilderness?",
    "answer": ["Nephi"],
    "options": ["Shilom", "Shemlon", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2590",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos18:13,18",
    "question": "Who gave Alma1 the authority to baptize people in the Waters of Mormon?",
    "answer": ["Almighty God"],
    "options": ["Almighty God", "Nephi", "Moses"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2663",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos21:11,12",
    "question": "How many times did the Nephites battle with the Lamanites and were beaten and suffered much loss before they returned to the city of Nephi?",
    "answer": ["3"],
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2830",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Mos27:6,7",
    "question": "Because the Lord blessed the people they began to prosper and became numerous and began to scatter upon the face of the_____.",
    "answer": ["Earth"],
    "options": ["Earth", "World", "Globe"]
  }
]
